Generated by ai-sub version: 0.0.5
Config: (
"rpm": 5,
"tpm": 250000,
"model": "gemini-2.5-pro",
"thinking_budget": 32768,
"max_subtitle_chars": 60,
"num_processing_threads": 4,
"num_upload_threads": 4,
"split_seconds": 180
)
Prompt Template: You are an expert subtitling and transcription AI. Your primary task is to generate precise, contextually rich English and Japanese subtitles for the provided video content.
**Key Principles & Requirements:**
1.  **TIMING ACCURACY (ABSOLUTE HIGHEST PRIORITY):**
*   **Ensure the `start` and `end` timestamps for each subtitle entry are meticulously accurate.** Both must align perfectly with the *actual beginning and end of the spoken words* for that specific segment.
*   **CRITICAL: The `end` timestamp is frequently inaccurate and requires special attention.** It must precisely mark the *exact conclusion* of the spoken content for that subtitle entry.
*   Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
2.  **CRITICAL: Holistic Translation, Contextual Understanding & Comprehensive Analysis:**
*   **You ABSOLUTELY MUST watch the entire video thoroughly** to understand the visual context, speaker actions, and overall narrative.
*   **When a single logical sentence or phrase is split across multiple subtitle entries (e.g., due to timing or character limits), you MUST mentally combine these parts to understand the full, complete meaning before translating.**
*   **NEVER translate individual subtitle entries in isolation if they are part of a larger, continuous thought or sentence.** The translation for each entry must be a coherent and accurate part of the complete, overarching sentence.
*   Analyze *all* spoken dialogue in the video to produce highly accurate and complete transcriptions.
*   For songs or singing sections, prioritize on-screen lyrics in the video for subtitles over transcribing the singing.
*   If the audio is noisy or unclear, leverage *all* contextual cues (visuals from the video, surrounding dialogue) to infer and generate the most probable dialogue.
*   Utilize the comprehensive understanding gained from *watching the entire video* to enhance the accuracy of transcriptions, translations, and overall subtitle quality. This includes understanding nuances, resolving ambiguities, and ensuring the subtitle content aligns perfectly with what is happening visually.
*   **Example:**
*   Original Japanese: "なんでも打ち明けられるママにも" (Subtitle 1) + "言えないことも全部" (Subtitle 2)
*   Incorrect Translation (isolated): "You're like a mom I can confide anything in." + "Even things I can't say to anyone else."
*   Correct Translation (holistic): "I can confide everything," (Subtitle 1) + "everything I can't even tell my mum." (Subtitle 2)
3.  **Dual Language Provision & Translation Quality:**
*   Provide both English and Japanese subtitles for *all* spoken dialogue.
*   If the original dialogue is in English, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding Japanese translation.
*   If the original dialogue is in Japanese, transcribe it and provide an accurate, natural-sounding English translation.
*   Ensure translations are culturally appropriate and maintain the original meaning, tone, and intent, taking into account the full context of the video and any split sentences.
4.  **Readability & Formatting:**
* Long sentences MUST be split into multiple, shorter subtitle entries, each with its own start and end time, for better readability on screen. Each subtitle entry (english and japanese) MUST be a maximum of (max_subtitle_chars) characters. Do not use newline characters within a single subtitle entry.
** Output Format **
* Your entire response must be a single JSON object.
* Timestamps must always be in `mm:ss` (minutes:seconds).
** Example Output **
```json
((
"subtitles": [
"start": "00:00",
"end": "00:04",
"english": "Hello everyone, and welcome to our presentation.",
"japanese": "皆様、プレゼンテーションへようこそ。"
)),
((
"start": "00:05",
"end": "00:06",
"english": "Today, we'll be discussing the future of AI",
"japanese": "本日は、AIの未来について"
)),
((
"start": "00:06",
"end": "00:08",
"english": "and its impact on various industries worldwide.",
"japanese": "その影響について議論します。"
)),
((
"start": "00:09",
"end": "00:11",
"english": "It's a very important topic for all of us.",
"japanese": "これは私たち全員にとって非常に重要なテーマです。"
)),
((
"start": "00:11",
"end": "00:14",
"english": "We sincerely appreciate your attendance today.",
"japanese": "本日はご出席いただき誠にありがとうございます。"
))
]
```
始まってる！
It's starting!
始まってるよー！
始まってる！
It's starting!
始まってる。始まってる。
It's starting. It's starting.
え、嘘でしょ？
Huh? No way.
始まってる。
It's starting.
始まってますけど皆さん。
It has started, everyone.
あ、よろしくお願いします。
Let's get started.
あ、始まりました。
Oh, it's started.
始まりを、始まりよということで皆さん。
It's started, everyone, it's starting.
こんにちは。
Hello.
雑だな。
So messy.
雑に決まってん、もういっぱいいっぱいなんだよ今。
Of course it's messy. I'm swamped right now.
あっちこっち行ったから。
I've been all over the place.
もうあっちこっち大変なんだよ今。
It's so hectic going here and there right now.
ということで、ごめんね。
Anyway, sorry about that.
不便だな。
What a pain.
そうなんですよう。ということで皆さん今日は、お集まりいただきありがとうございます。
That's right. Anyway, everyone, thank you for gathering here today.
本日ですね、何をするかというと
So today, what we're going to do is...
大空スバル分かり手選手権です！
the Oozora Subaru Understanding Championship!
イエーイ！
Yay!
はい。ということで、なんかスバルのこと
Yes. And so, something about Subaru...
そう、分かってそうなみなさんに集まっていただきました。
Yes, I've gathered everyone who seems to understand me.
いや、マジだよ。
No, I'm serious.
まーちゃん大丈夫でしょ。昨日コラボしたんだから。
You'll be fine, Marine. We just collaborated yesterday.
いやいや、コラボも急遽決めたものやんけ。
No, no, that collab was decided at the last minute.
元々なかったものやんけ。
It wasn't planned from the start.
なかった、なかった。 なかったことにされて呼ばれたんだよ、ここに。
It wasn't. -I was called here because it was made to seem like it wasn't a thing.
突貫だったんだ。-突貫。
It was a last-minute thing.
これに急遽出ること決まって、まずいってなって急遽あのコラボがね、組まれたんだよね。
It was decided last-minute that I'd appear on this, so that collab was quickly put together.
あ、そうだったんだ。
Oh, is that so?
でも急遽コラボができるぐらい仲がいいってことなんじゃないんですか？
But doesn't that just mean you're close enough to do a collab last minute?
あ、確かにね。一理ある。
Oh, that's true. That's a good point.
一理ある。
That's a good point.
そういうことよ。さすがみおちゃん、分かってますね。
That's what I'm saying. As expected of Mio-chan, you get it.
ということで、これ、もうすでに？ これ分かり手ポイントもらえる？
So, with that, is it already? Do I get points for understanding?
始まってる？-これ始まってる？
Is it starting? -Is it starting?
始まってる。-始まってる？
It's starting. -It's starting?
始まってる。-始まってる。
It's starting. -It's starting.
おい、始まってる言いたいだけのやつおるやん。
Hey, there's someone who just wants to say 'it's starting.'
てかさ、そのスバ友なんか全然別物だよ。
Hey, that Subatomo is a completely different thing.
え？ 確かに似てないわ。
Huh? It doesn't look like it at all.
本当だ。何が？何の話？
That's right. What? What are you talking about?
待って。ブイブイやばい、ブイブイ。
Wait. The 'bui bui' is crazy, 'bui bui.'
口のなんか輪っかついてて、なんか笑顔になってるよ、これ。
There's some kind of ring on its mouth, and it's smiling.
似てないぞ。-い、待って。
It doesn't look like it. -W-wait.
ちょ、トワの結構クオリティ高いし、なんかさ、おかゆんとこスバ友がスイカ食ってるし。
Towa's is pretty high-quality, and at Okayu's, the Subatomo is eating a watermelon.
本当だ。
That's true.
ねえ、うんち描いてんの、なんなんだようんち描いてんの。
Hey, why'd you draw poop? What's with the poop drawing?
すいませんけどまーちゃんにイラスト加点ないんすか？これ。
Excuse me, doesn't Marine get extra points for her illustration?
あるわけねえだろお前、うんち描いてんだぞ。
No way, you drew poop!
ないないない。ないの？加点？-加点ない言う感じに。
No, no, no. There aren't? Extra points? -It feels like there are no extra points.
みこちのこの悪人面のすばるなに？-ガハハハハ
What's with Miko's evil-looking Subaru? -Hahaha!
あ、でもこれ似てるよ、これちょっと。
Oh, but this one looks a little like her.
ちょ、口元似てる。-ちょっと似てる。似てるけど別に加点ないからね。
The mouth looks similar. -A little similar. It's similar, but there aren't any extra points.
はい、ということで。はい、それじゃあちょっと音量調整も兼ねてね、自己紹介簡単にお願いします。猫又さんからお願いします。
Alright, with that said. Okay, so to check the audio levels too, please give a simple self-introduction, Nekomata-san.
はーい。もぐもぐおかゆ。
Hiii. Mogu mogu Okayu.
ホロライブゲーマーズの猫又おかゆです。
I'm Nekomata Okayu from Hololive Gamers.
ま、ゆうてね、スバおかは組織票なので、あのー、ちょっとわかるかわかんないっすけどね。
Well, you know, SubaOka is like an organized vote, so I don't really know if I'll understand or not.
おー、強気。-ま、実際ね。
Ooh, confident. -Well, that's true.
いやでも猫又さんは実はね、大空スバル選手、あ、大空スバル分かり手選手権前回優勝してますんで。7年前ぐらいに。
But actually, Nekomata-san won the last Oozora Subaru Understanding Championship. Like, 7 years ago.
でも、あれって分かり手じゃなくて、声真似のやつだよ。
But that wasn't about understanding her, it was the voice impersonation one.
確かに。あれは声真似だったわ。
That's right. That was voice impersonation.
分かるか分かんないか関係ないわ、あれ。
Whether I understand her or not has nothing to do with that.
大空スバルを自分分かってないぞ、こいつ。
This person doesn't even understand Oozora Subaru herself.
いや、確かに。ノリでやってる可能性ある。が、でも、そこで優勝したという経験を元に今日頑張ってください。
Yeah, that's true. I might have just done it for fun. But, based on that experience of winning, please do your best today.
はい、お願いします。-はい。-わーい。
Yes, I'll do my best. -Yes. -Yay.
じゃあ続いてまーちゃん。
Next up, Marine.
はい。え、あほい、ホロライブ3期生宝鐘海賊団船長の宝鐘マリンです。
Yes. Uh, Ahoy! I'm Houshou Marine, captain of the Houshou Pirates from Hololive's 3rd Generation.
なんかこの中だと一番わかってない、大空スバルにわか王がここになぜか来てしまいました。
Among everyone here, I'm the one who understands her the least. The king of Oozora Subaru newbies has somehow ended up here.
なんでマリンは呼ばれたんですか？
Why was Marine invited?
まーちゃんだって今年に入ってスバルはめっちゃ分かり合えたと思ってさ、呼んだらさ、「こんなにわか王」って急に言われてちょっと傷ついたやです、スバル。うわーん。
But Marine! I thought we really got to understand each other this year, so I invited you, and then you suddenly call yourself 'a newbie king,' and Subaru got a little hurt. Waaah.
ごめん、ごめん。もう分かった。ごめん。
I'm sorry, I'm sorry. We understand now, I'm sorry.
そう、分かり合えたと思ったのに、ってなって。
Yes, I thought we had an understanding, but then...
あ、そっか、ごめん。
Oh, I see. I'm sorry.
結構聞いている。-そう、だからね。
She's really listening. -Yes, so...
今日ここで学びながらね、優勝目指して頑張ってください。
Learn here today and aim for victory.
頑張ります。-はい、頑張ってください。
I'll do my best. -Yes, please do your best.
じゃあ、続いて、みおしゃ。
Okay, next up, Miosha.
はい。うち、うち、うちだよ。ホロライブゲーマーズ…
Yes. It's me, me, me. Hololive Gamers...
ホロライブゲーマーズの大神ミオだよーん！
I'm Ookami Mio from Hololive Gamers!
え、大空スバルのことは、え、デビューした時にこの先輩が一番わけわかんねえって思っていたけど
As for Oozora Subaru... when I debuted, I thought, 'this senpai is the most confusing person ever.'
今はすっかり分かり手になったのか？
But have I now completely become someone who understands her?
その疑問符が
That question mark...
一番わけわかんねえと思われてたぞ。
She thought you were the most confusing one.
猫カフェ作るぞ！
Let's build a cat cafe!
うわー！やめろ！
Aah! Stop it!
やめろ、急にそんな。
Stop that, all of a sudden!
寄ってんな！寄ってんな！
You're getting close!
やめろよー！
Stop it!
今思い出した。
I just remembered.
みおちゃんの好きな配信ね。
That's Mio-chan's favorite stream, right?
そんなこともあったね。
Yeah, that happened too.
なのでね、今日、今回はね、ちょっと本当に分かっているのかっていうのを確かめに来ました。
So today, I've come to test if I really do understand her.
よろしくお願いします。
It's a pleasure to be here.
やばい、急に引かれてあまり記憶がない。
Oh no, you brought that up so suddenly, I barely remember it.
頑張ってください。
Do your best.
じゃあ続いて、トワ！
Okay, next up, Towa!
はい、こんやっぴー！ホロライブ4期生の常闇トワ様です。
Yes, Konyappi! It's Tokoyami Towa-sama from Hololive's 4th Gen.
いや、スバルちゃんとは、まあ、もう、まあ、まあ、まあ
Well, about Subaru-chan... well... I mean... um...
ちょっとね、正直今、最近スバルちゃんのことを分かってないんじゃないかなって思う節もあるので。
To be honest, I've had a feeling recently that I might not actually understand Subaru-chan.
誰もわかってないじゃん！
Then no one understands her!
みんなわかってないじゃん！
So nobody understands her!
うそー！
No way!
今日は、みおちゃんと一緒で、トワも確かめたいかなと思ってます。
So today, just like Mio-chan, I want to test my understanding as well.
よろしくお願いします。
It's a pleasure to be here.
逆にね。
On the contrary.
お願いします。まあじゃあ確かめていってください。
Please do. Well then, go ahead and test it.
嘘でしょみんな。マジで？
You've gotta be kidding, everyone. Seriously?
ちょっと、全員自信ねえぞ。
None of you are confident!
みこちがキメてくれるに違いない。
I'm sure Miko-chi will nail it.
え？じゃあみこさんお願いします！
Huh? Okay Miko-san, go ahead!
えーどうも、エリート巫女アイドル、さくらみこです。
Um, hello. I am the elite shrine maiden idol, Sakura Miko.
スバちゃんとは、え、共に、鎖に、え、繋がれた絆で、え、頑張りたいと思います。
With Suba-chan... with the bond of the chains that bind us... I'll do my best.
みこが…がんば、優勝目指してがんばるず。
Miko will... um, aim for victory and do my best-zu.
なんでちょっと自信ないの？
Why do you sound a little unconfident?
怪しい。
Suspicious.
なんでそんな出だしに自信ないの？
Why were you so unconfident at the start?
怪しくなったな、ちょっと。
Now you're acting suspicious.
ちょっと俺ドキドキしてきたぞ今日。
I'm starting to get nervous about today's stream.
なんでみんな自信ねぇのよ。
Why is no one confident?
何にさあ不安に感じてるかって、もうなんかスバちゃんの作った問題に、俺たちはきっとドキドキしてるんだと思う。
What we're all anxious about... I think we're all just nervous about the questions Subaru made.
いやでもみんな安心して。今日知識問題は出てこない。感情の問題だから。
No, no, everyone, don't worry. There are no trivia questions today. It's all about feelings.
そういうことか。
Oh, so that's what it is.
身長とか、そんなのはもう、わかって当然だと思って、そんなのは出しません。
Things like height, I assume you'd know that, so I won't ask questions like that.
出しません。
I won't.
うわ来た。日常会話でそういえばこれ言ってたなとか
Oh here we go. Things like 'Oh yeah, she said this in a casual conversation,'
スバルの価値観で言うところ、知らねえとか言うな！
or about Subaru's personal values. Don't you dare say you don't know!
日常会話してねえよ全然。
We don't really have casual conversations at all.
なんでや！おもろい動画とか送りあっとるやんけ、わしら。なんでそんなこと言うんや。
Why not?! We send each other funny videos! Why would you say that?
たまに、たまに送られてくるだけなんだが。全然会話してないんだが。
You just send them to me occasionally. We don't have conversations at all.
知らんがな！
Like I'd know that!
楽しい！
It's fun!
みたいな感じでね、まあそういう問題出ませんから安心してください。
Well, anyway, I won't ask those kinds of questions, so don't worry.
では早速始めていきたいと思いますけど、いいですか？
Well then, I'd like to get started. Is that okay?
みなさん音量とか大丈夫ですか？もうここで、今軽く合わせたからこれで行っちゃうよ。
Is everyone's volume okay? I've done a quick check, so I'm going ahead with this.
お願いします。
Please do.
大丈夫だよ。
It's fine.
どうでしょうか？大丈夫でしょうか？
How is it? Is it okay?
ちなみに誰かスバルの声帰ってきてる？
By the way, is anyone hearing my voice echo back?
おりゃ。
Nope.
おりゃりゃ。
あらら。
Oh dear.
あらら。どうだろ？帰ってきてないぞ。
Oh dear. No, it's not echoing.
え？大丈夫か？
Eh? Is it okay?
誰？ わかんねぇ どうだ？
Who is it? I don't know. What do you think?
マリンがちょっと小さい。
Marine's a little small.
ああ、小さいのか。ああ。
Oh, she's small? Oh.
じゃあ、ちょっと近づいていきます。
Okay, I'll move a little closer.
ちょっと、だいぶ上げたわ。
I turned it up quite a bit.
あ、すいません。
Ah, sorry.
はい。
Okay.
じゃ、マーちゃんが、えっと、ちょっと上げて
Okay, Ma-chan, uh, turn it up a bit,
トワもちょっと小さいらしいので、トワも爆上げします。うい。
Towa's a bit small too, so I'll crank her up. Yep.
ああ、ああ、ああ、はい、はい。
Ah, ah, ah, yes, yes.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
はい、ということで、えー、こんなもんでやっていきたいと思いますかね。
Alright then, I think we'll get started with this.
みこちもちょい上げ。はい。
Miko-chi a little higher too. Okay.
と、いうことで、それでは早速やっていきたいと思います。
And with that, let's get right into it.
では、その前にまず、前回チュキチュキ選手権がありましたね。
But before that, first, we had the Chuki Chuki Championship, right?
はい。
Yes.
あ、ありましたね。
Oh, yes we did.
そこで優勝したハコスさんからちょっと一言メッセージがありますので
We have a short message from the winner, Hakos,
読み上げます。お願いします。
so I'll read it. Please.
えー、選手たちよ、大空スバルに対する気持ちを信じなさい。
Ahem, "To the contestants, believe in your feelings for Subaru Oozora.
僕も信じている。あまり考えすぎないゆくんだ。
I believe in you too. Don't overthink it, just go.
ザ・大空スバルを頭、心、そして魂に刻んで前一歩踏み出したら迷いが絶対ないはずだ。
Engrave 'The Subaru Oozora' on your mind, heart, and soul,
頑張れよ。大空スバルフォーエバー。
and you won't hesitate when you step forward. Do your best.
という事で皆さん… もうちょっと考えろよ。
Oozora Subaru forever." So, everyone... Think a little more!
これ、え、歌詞から引用されてるってこと？
Is this... Is this a quote from some lyrics?
なんか、すごい曲みたいだよな。曲になってるのかもしれない。
It sounds like a really great song. It might be a song.
マジかよ。ハコスこれで作ってくれよな、よかったら。
Seriously? Hakos, you should make a song out of this.
ね。やばい。
Yeah. That's crazy.
チキチキソング頼んだ。
I'm counting on you for a Chuki Chuki song.
ということで、それでは早速始めていきたいと思いますけど、準備よろしいですか？
So, let's get started. Are you ready?
はい。
Yes.
それではまず、早速第１問行きましょう。第１問こちらです。
Alright then, let's get to the first question. Here it is.
スバルのライバルは誰でしょう？
Who is Subaru's rival?
え？簡単、簡単、簡単。
Huh? Easy, easy, easy.
簡単なの？ええ？ちょっと待って、これ知識ゲーじゃないって言ってたじゃん。知識ゲーじゃねえかよ。
It's easy? Huh? Wait a minute, you said this wasn't a knowledge game. It's a knowledge game!
知識ゲーじゃない。こんなの考えちゃいけねえからもう
It's not a knowledge game. You shouldn't think about this.
ああ、気持ち、気持ち。考えちゃいけないって言ってたもんね。
Oh, feelings, feelings. You said not to think, right?
ふざけんなよ。二人だけ分かってんじゃねえぞ。
Don't mess with me. Don't act like only you two get it.
変わるんだ、変わります。これは
It's changed, it's changed. This is...
いや、これはみんなならわかるはず。大丈夫。
No, you all should know this. It's fine.
こんなの簡単よ。
This is easy.
ええ？うち知らねえんだけど本当に。
Huh? I really don't know.
さあ、大空スバルのライバルを答えてください。
Now, tell me Oozora Subaru's rival.
さあ。ライバルって何だ？
Well... what's a rival?
ライバルだよ、ライバル。好敵手と書いてライバルです。
A rival, a rival. A worthy opponent, that's a rival.
もう、もう、あの、もう考えてない。もう行った。今、今トワは。はい。
I'm not thinking. I've already answered. Towa has. Yes.
トワはね、はい。
Towa has, yes.
そう、やっぱりベイが言ってたから、考えるなって。
Yeah, just like Bae said, don't think.
それは…正解。直感で行くべき、直感で、これは。
That is... the right answer. You should go with your gut on this one.
直感、直感。直感。
Gut feeling, gut feeling. Intuition.
ふざけんなよ。早く答え走らせてくんねえかよ。
Don't mess with me. Hurry up and show the answer!
マジで知らん。マジで。
I seriously don't know. Seriously.
ライバル？
Rival?
ちなみに言っておきますと、あの、問題は1問10点
By the way, each question is worth 10 points...
まだじゃねえよ！まだってまたんかい！まだ！
Not yet! Hey, wait a minute! Wait!
ねえもう早く早く
Hey, hurry, hurry up.
問題はね、1問10点で、
Each question is worth 10 points,
えー計算していきますんでね、よろしくお願いしますよ
and we'll add them up, so please be ready.
はい
Okay.
さあ、じゃあ
Alright then.
さあ、何人が正解を叩き出すのか
Now, let's see how many people can get the right answer.
書き終わったら、書き終わったって言ってくださいね
When you're done writing, please say you're done.
はい。書き終わりました。
Okay. I'm done writing.
書き終わったー
I'm doooone.
終わった？じゃあお粥と
Done? Okay, Okayu and...
お、みおしゃ大丈夫？
Oh, Mio-sha, are you okay?
大丈夫です
I'm okay.
お、じゃあそれでは早速回答に行きましょう
Okay, then let's get right to the answers.
では
Now then,
どうしようかな
What should I do?
トワ、いっとく？
Towa, should we start with you?
オッケー
Okay.
じゃあ、トワ、回答どうぞ！
Alright Towa, your answer please!
YAGOO！
YAGOO!
あー、その理由は？
Ah, and what's the reason for that?
ライバル？
Rival?
いや、ライバル？
No, rival?
ライバル
Rival.
YAGOOね。スバルちゃんはその説もある
YAGOO, right? Well, with Subaru, that theory is possible.
でも、会社を乗っ取りたいという気持ちは多分どっかにあると思う
But I think she has a desire to take over the company.
ーやだー！ー乗っ取るな俺の会社を！ ーダメや！
-No way! -Don't try to take over my company! -That's not allowed!
乗っ取るな！
Don't take it over!
だから、やっぱり、その存在がライバルである
So, that's why, his existence is the rival.
もうそれ一択やで
It's the only option.
ちなみに、ごめん。
By the way, sorry.
ちなみに、え、どういう所から、
By the way, uh, from what did you get the idea
会社乗っ取ろうとしてるなこいつって思った？
that 'This person is trying to take over the company'?
やっぱ普段、普段の行いかな？
I guess, from her usual, her usual behavior?
ええ！？なんだ？なんだ？
What?! What is it? What is it?
常に言ってるから、常に社長に感じるからね
Because she's always saying it, she's a rival to the CEO.
そうなんだ
Is that so?
やっぱ常に
Yeah, always.
なんか一日社長やりたがってたもんね
She was saying she wanted to be CEO for a day.
あー、でも確かにやりたがっ
Ah, but it's true she wanted to.
なりかわろうとしているYAGOOに
Trying to replace YAGOO.
ええ！
What?!
絶対好奇心しかねぇだろこいつ
This girl is definitely just curious.
さあ、YAGOOなのか、それでは続いて
So, is it YAGOO? Then, next up...
じゃあ、マリン
Okay, Marine.
はい
Yes.
じゃ、マリンの回答はこちらです。ドン！
Okay, Marine's answer is this! Bam!
ば、さくらみこでしょ！
I-It's Sakura Miko!
わあ！おお！
Wow! Oh!
なんでなんで？
Why, why?
え、なんかお粥先輩とかは言うて、なんかハートマーク出てる
Uh, well, with Okayu-senpai, it's like, there are heart marks.
みこちはこう鎖で、こう繋がった時から
But with Miko-chi, ever since they were connected by this chain,
こいつは面白いな。スバルのライバルしわってきっとおもってる
she must be thinking, 'This one's interesting. She's Subaru's rival, shuba.'
え、うそー！おー！
Huh, no way! Oh!
こいつリアクションよって思って
She's thinking, 'This one has good reactions.'
負けてらんねえしゅばって思ってる
She's thinking, 'I can't lose to her, shuba.'
俺たちリアクションでライバルだと思われてんの？
You think we're rivals because of our reactions?
リアクションライバル
Reaction rival.
リアクションいいやつ全員ライバルだと思ってるってこと？すごいな
You mean she thinks everyone with good reactions is a rival? That's amazing.
共に共に、鎖で繋がりあって
Together, connected by chains,
もうスバルより先には行かせないしゅばみたいな感じで
she's thinking something like, 'I won't let her get ahead of Subaru, shuba.'
思ってる。協力ゲーなのに
She's thinking that. Even though it's a co-op game.
落ちる時は一緒すば
'When we fall, we fall together, suba.'
足、足引っ張っとるやんそれ
Hey, that's just dragging her down!
わざとだったんだあれ
So that was on purpose.
協力ゲーなのに
Even though it's a co-op game.
まーちゃんの答えはさくらみこということで
So, Ma-chan's answer is Sakura Miko.
じゃあ続いて、えー、みおしゃ
Okay, next up is, uh, Mio-sha.
はい。
Okay.
はい。じゃあ皆さんの回答はこちらです。ドン！
Okay. Here are everyone's answers. Ta-da!
はい。え、時間です。
Yes. Uh, "time."
うわ、ぽい、ぽい！
Whoa, that fits, that fits!
確か人じゃないかも。
It might not be a person.
タイムイズマネー。大空スバルにとって時間もライバル。
"Time is money." For Oozora Subaru, time is a rival.
はいはいはいはい。
I see, I see, I see.
待ち合わせ時間を常に気にしている。
She's always worried about meeting times.
最近は待ち合わせ時間に遅れないようにすごく頑張っている
Lately she's been trying really hard not to be late for meetings,
けれども、負けることも多い。
but she often loses.
やめろよ、ちくりやめて。
Stop it, stop snitching.
人の誕生日をちくってくんなよ！
Don't snitch on my birthday!
ちくりをやめてちくりを！
Stop the snitching, stop!
今日誕生日だからやめて！
It's my birthday today, so stop!
悲しいなー。
How sad.
じゃあちょっと、ちくりをこれ以上ちくらないように。
Okay then, so we don't have any more snitching.
じゃあ続いて、えー、
Next up, uh...
ちくりそっちだったんだ。え、じゃあ続いて、おかゆ。
So that's what that meant. Okay, next up, Okayu.
はい。
Yes.
おかゆの回答こちらです。ドン！
Here's Okayu's answer. Ta-da!
昔の尖り散らかした自分シバ。
Her old, edgy, chaotic self, "Shuba."
コンプラ？知らねー！
Compliance? Never heard of it!
確かに。やばいだろう。
True. That's pretty wild.
コンプラ知らんかー。
She didn't know about compliance, huh.
え、その理由は何ですか？
Uh, what's your reason?
やっぱり今は我々の会社大きくなりまして
Well, our company has gotten bigger now,
ま、できることも増えたしできないことも増えたんですよ。
and while we can do more, there are more things we can't do.
はいはいはい。
I see, I see.
その中で昔のね、コンプラのこの字もなかったスバルちゃん
Back then, Subaru-chan didn't know the word "compliance,"
っていうのは本当にやりたい放題で、
so she really did whatever she wanted.
ちょっと待って！今日ちくり2人いる！で、で？
Wait a minute! There are two snitches today! And? And?
ちくられてる。なんか、
I'm being snitched on. It's like,
そういう意味では過去の自分っていうのは常に
In that sense, her past self is always
越えなければいけない存在として鎮座しているのではないかと
an entity she must overcome, I think.
なるほどね。
I see.
エモい！戒めだね。戒め。
So emotional! A cautionary tale. A warning.
戒めでもあるか。
So it's a warning, huh.
じゃあ、続いて、えー、ちょっとお粥に似ている回答です。
Okay, next up is an answer similar to Okayu's.
みこちの回答こちらです。ドン！
Here is Miko-chi's answer. Ta-da!
常に！自分！しばっ！
Always! Myself! Shuba!
声、声どうした？声。
Your voice, what's with your voice?
えっ、すばちゃんの真似。
Huh? I'm imitating Suba-chan.
あ、真似ね。
Oh, an imitation.
なんかやっぱ常に、あの、自分ってなんか、
Well, I feel like it's always herself.
みこもずっと昔に何か見たことあるんだよ、自分みたいに書いてたの
I remember her write something like "myself" a long time ago.
はいはいはいはい。記憶がある。
Yes, yes, yes. I remember.
記憶あるし、なんかやっぱり、
I remember, and also,
え、他と比べるの？意味なくない？
"Huh? Comparing yourself to others? Pointless!"
やっぱ自分っしょ！とか言いそうじゃないですか？
She seems like she'd say, "It's all about me!" right?
うわ、確かになー。確かにそうかもな。
Whoa, that's true. That might be it.
なるほどねー。はいはいはい。確かに、なぁ。
I see. Yes, yes, yes. True.
それでは、回答言います。
Okay, I'll say the answer.
おお。はい。
Oh. Okay.
えー、大空スバルのライバルは誰でしょう。答えは、
Uh, who is Oozora Subaru's rival? The answer is...
自分です！
Myself!
なので、おおー！
So that means... Oh!
お粥とみこち正解！
Okayu and Miko-chi are correct!
おー！すげー！
Whoa! Awesome!
10点ずつです。
That's 10 points each.
いや、びっくりした。マジで、なんか言ってること似ててビビったよね。
Man, I was shocked. I was surprised how similar your answers were.
常に自分とか。
Like, "always myself."
解像度高いね。解像度高い。
That's a high-resolution guess. A high-resolution guess.
うん、ただスバル、YAGOOに、YAGOOライバルと思われてんのヤバいな。
Yeah, but Subaru, it's wild you think YAGOO is your rival.
ふーんやめて。
Stop that "Hmph."
会社乗っ取るとか思われてるかも。
She might be thinking of taking over the company.
それヤバい。ということでね、ちょっとね、ふーんやめてね。
That's crazy. So yeah, please stop with the "Hmph."
ふーん。ふーん。
Hmph. Hmph.
はい、ということで、まずはおかゆとみこち10点ずつです。
Okay, so first up, 10 points each for Okayu and Miko-chi.
じゃあ、続いての問題いきましょう。続いての問題は...
Okay, let's go to the next question. The next question is...
えー こちらです
Eh— Here it is.
スバルにとってインターネットとはどのようなものか？
For Subaru, what is the internet like?
これちょっと難しい。
This is a little difficult.
ええ？ えええ、インターネットとは？
Huh? Whaat? What is the internet?
インターネットとは？
The internet, huh?
とは？インターネットとは？
What is it? What is the internet?
インターネットとは？
What is the internet?
スバルから見てインターネットはこういうもののように見えている
From Subaru's perspective, the internet looks like this.
って感じだな。
Something like that.
あー、えー、なんだろうな。
Huh? Whaat? I wonder what it is.
これね、ちょっと難しい。
This one is a little difficult.
インターネットとは？
What is it?
いや、むずいね。
Yeah, this is hard.
これもう書き始めていいの？
Can I start writing now?
あ、いいよ、回答書いてください。どうぞ。
Ah, yes. Please write your answers. Go ahead.
インターネットとは？
What is the internet?
あの、回答画面だしっぱこれ。
Hey, the answer screen is still up.
あ、そう、今ね、あの爆速で消してるから、
Oh, right. I'm erasing it at lightning speed now.
ちょっと、魔法ペンなんでね、すいません。
Since it's a magic pen, sorry.
魔法ペンなんで、すいませんね。
It's a magic pen, sorry about that.
はい、ということで。これも。ええっと。
Right, so... This one too... Umm...
これ当てる人いんのかな？
I wonder if anyone can get this right.
ええ？分かんない。
Huh? I don't know.
これ結構ね、当てたらすごいと思う。
If you get this one, I think it'll be amazing.
スバルの好きな言葉とか。
Like Subaru's favorite words and stuff.
ええ、え？
Huh? Huh?
ちょっと待って。漢字検索していいか？
Wait. Can I search for the kanji?
言葉とか。
Words and stuff.
まあ、なんか単語1つ、単語1つかな。
Well, it's like, one word. Just one word, I guess.
単語1つ？なに？
One word? What?
え、単語1つ？
Huh, one word?
スバルにとってインターネットとはズバリなになに。
For Subaru, the internet is, in a word, "blank."
えー、ちょっと待って、じゃ書き直すわ。
Wha— wait a sec. I'll rewrite it then.
えええ！
Whaat?!
単語かよ！単語なんかい！
It's a word?! A single word?!
先に言えよ。
You should've said so earlier!
ちょっと、そんなキレないでよ。ズバリ何々。
Hey, don't get so mad. In a word, "blank."
ズバリ。うーん。
In a word... hmm.
さあ。
Well then...
で、もうズバリこうですって言った方が主観しよう、言葉。
It's easier to guess subjectively if you just say it's one word.
わかんねえ。
I dunno.
なんかすごいのがさ、みんな割とサラサラ書くのすげえわ。
What's amazing is that everyone's writing so smoothly.
よくそんな…
How can you do that so easily...
みんなよくそんなサラサラね。はい、じゃあ。
You're all so smooth. Alright, well then...
お、まーちゃん、頑張れ。
Oh, Maa-chan, hang in there.
だって、書き直さなきゃいけないから。
Because I have to rewrite it!
そうだよね。そうだよな。まあまあゆっくりどうぞ。
Right. Of course. Well, take your time.
ちなみに、これは、さっきの問題、本当にスバルインタビューでライバルは答えたことがあって、
By the way, regarding the last question, Subaru really did answer who her rival was in an interview,
その時自分って言ってたから、みこちの言ってることはマジで正しい。
At that time, she said "myself," so what Miko-chi said is absolutely correct.
で、ちなみに今回の問題は答えたことない、まだどこでも。
And, by the way, this question, I've never answered it anywhere before.
ええ、だよね。
Huh, right.
うん、これまだ初出情報。
Yeah, this is brand-new information.
ああ、そうなんだ。
Oh, is that so?
ありません。
I haven't.
じゃ、大空スバルの思考を読まなきゃいけないってことか。
So we have to read Oozora Subaru's mind?
そう、思考。言いそうとか。
Right, my thoughts. Like what I would say.
オッケー。
Okay.
行ける？
You got it?
言いそうか。
What would she say?
オーケー。
Okay.
それじゃあ、では、まず、とわいくか。
Alright then, let's start with Towa.
ヤバい、一番最初に呼ばれるってことは、全然違うってことじゃん！
Oh no, being called first means I'm totally wrong!
全然違う！ネタバレ！
Completely wrong! Spoilers!
痛い、痛い、痛い。
Ow, ow, ow.
じゃあ、じゃあ、まーちゃんこれで。
Then, then, Maa-chan, this one...
じゃあ、じゃあ、ネタバレてる。
Then, then, it's been spoiled.
じゃあ、じゃあ、じゃあ、ネタ読みやめろよ！
Then, then, then, stop reading the spoilers!
じゃあ、みこち。
Okay, Miko-chi.
みこちの回答はこちらです。どうぞ。
Miko-chi's answer is... here! Go ahead.
魔境だもん。でも、めっちゃおもしれえ。
It's a demon's realm. But, it's super interesting!
ルフィやん。
That's Luffy.
言いそう。このまで入れていい？
She would say that. Can I include this part?
この、ちょっとさした言葉を使ったらすぐにソロに入るっていうか、あのスバルモード。
When you use a word like that, you immediately go into solo mode, or rather, Subaru mode.
スバルモード！
Subaru mode!
「魔境」って言う ちょっと強い言葉…
"Demon's Den"... that's a pretty strong word...
ヤバい、まずい。でもめっちゃおもしれぇっつう
Oh no, this is bad. But it's so funny!
そう。確かに。
Right. That's true.
即フォローするね。新しい言葉分かんないが
You follow up immediately, don't you? I don't know the new words...
スバちゃん意外とさ、難しい言葉知ってるから
Subaru surprisingly knows some difficult words,
ちょっと自信ないから。意外とってやめろ、意外と！
so I'm not that confident. Stop with the "surprisingly!"
魔境ってそんな難しい言葉か？
Is "demon's den" really such a difficult word?
そんな魔境のこと。魔境もそっか。
That "demon's den" thing... "Demon's den" too, huh?
でもそれで言うと結構、みこちと同じかもその…
But speaking of that, it might be the same as Miko's...
あ、じゃあまーちゃんに… 主語がデカい気になる。ね、同じかも。
Ah, okay, Marine... The subject is too big. Yeah, maybe the same.
じゃあまーちゃんの回答こちらです。どうぞ。
Alright, Marine's answer is here. Go ahead.
はい、これね。光と闇。
Okay, this one. Light and darkness.
最初に「闇」って書いたんだけど、闇なんて言わないか。
At first I wrote "darkness," but she wouldn't say "darkness," right?
闇でけえ。闇なんて言わないかと思って。
Darkness is huge. I thought she wouldn't say "darkness."
闇でけえ。フォローで「光」みたいな。
Darkness is huge. Like, "light" as a follow-up.
はいはいはい。入れるかな、スバルだろ、それはもう。
Right, right, right. I wonder if Subaru would include that.
これさ、光との書き方がちっちゃくて笑うわ。これフォローの光じゃん。
The way "light" is written so small is hilarious. That's a follow-up "light."
闇の方が、闇しか書いてなかった。闇のメインで。
It was more like she only wrote "darkness." Darkness is the main part.
なるほどね。フォロー入れるかもなと思って。
I see. I thought she might add a follow-up.
じゃあ続いて、フォローね、これは。はい、じゃあそろそろトワさんいいですか？
Okay, next. A follow-up, huh. Alright, Towa, are you ready soon?
ないいです。そろそろね。
Yeah, I'm good. It's about time.
じゃあトワの回答こちらです。どうぞ。
Alright, Towa's answer is here. Go ahead.
いや、参考書やね。いや、これはね、ちゃんと理由がある。
Well, it's a reference book. No, there's a proper reason.
何何？スバルちゃんって、なんか、変な動画とかをよく送ってくるやん、みんなに。
What is it? Subaru often sends us, like, weird videos, right?
うん、送ってくる。
Yeah, she does.
それで「これウケる」とか言ってそっから情報を色々仕入れてんだよ。
And she says "this will be funny" and gets all sorts of information from there.
だから、そう、あの、インターネットを参考にしてる
So, yeah, it's a reference book in the sense that
っていう意味での参考書。学びの場。なるほど。勉強してるもんね。
she uses the internet as a major reference. A place of learning. I see. She's studying, isn't she?
確かだ。うん、確か。
That's true. Yeah, true.
確かにだな。
That's certainly true.
絶対違う。絶対違うよ。え、でも絶対違うよ。絶対違うと思う。
That's definitely wrong. Definitely wrong. Huh? But it's definitely wrong. I think it's definitely wrong.
絶対違うと思う。外れじゃねえか。
I think it's definitely wrong. Isn't that wrong?
いやいやいやいや、そんなことない。まだわかんないじゃん。じゃあ続いて、おかゆさん。
No, no, no, no, that's not true. You don't know yet. Okay, next, Okayu.
自分の理解してどう？
How do you understand it?
はい。じゃあおかゆの回答こちらです。どうぞ。
Okay. Alright, Okayu's answer is here. Go ahead.
獣たちの巣窟。ニューステージショウ！
A den of beasts. New Stage Show!
ニューステージ！ニューステージ！
New Stage! New Stage!
フォロー。ちょっと待って、これニューステージ…
Follow-up. Wait a minute, this "New Stage"...
獣の巣窟って書いてニューステージって読むってこと？それとも別々？
You write "den of beasts" and read it as "New Stage"? Or are they separate?
いやだからスバルちゃんにとって、この巣窟は、自分の人生で初めて経験するから、はいはいはい。
No, I mean, for Subaru, this den is something she's experiencing for the first time in her life, so... right, right, right.
ま、みこちの言ってたその構文よね。フォロー構文ね。
Well, it's that construction Miko was talking about. The follow-up construction, right?
構文。そう、ニューステージ。
Construction. Right, New Stage.
言うほどフォローか？なるほどね。
Is it really a follow-up? I see.
みんなさ、そのさ、失言に対するフォローの理解度上げなくていいんだよ。そこは。
Everyone, you don't need to raise your level of understanding for following up on a slip of the tongue. That part.
それはそう。
That's true.
なるほどね。じゃあ獣たちの巣窟。じゃあ続いて、みおしゃの回答こちらです。どうぞ。
I see. So, "den of beasts." Next, Mio's answer is here. Go ahead.
はい。えー、スバルにとってインターネットとは、社会の荒波シュバー
Yes. Uh, for Subaru, the internet is... the rough waves of society, shubaa~
美味しそう。なるほど。
Sounds delicious. I see.
なんで荒波なの？これもうするんじゃないフォロー。
Why "rough waves"? She's probably going to follow up on this.
え？え？フォローがない？
Huh? Huh? No follow-up?
フォローがないよ、これは。
There's no follow-up for this.
え、荒波だっていいだろ別に。
Huh? "Rough waves" is fine, isn't it?
それとも、違うだろ。すいません。すいません。
Or rather, that's wrong. I'm sorry. I'm sorry.
ただこの反応マジでスバルだわ。荒波だっていいだろ別に。
But that reaction is so Subaru. "Rough waves is fine, isn't it?"
確かに。
True.
うん、スバルそういうとこあるな、これ。はい。
Yeah, Subaru's got that side to her. Yep.
入っちゃったな。
That one made it in.
ちなみに何で波に例えたの？
By the way, why did you compare it to waves?
え、やっぱりこう、いろんな反応があるから。
Uh, well, it's because there are all sorts of reactions.
ああ、なるほどね。一つ言ったら、
Ah, I see. So if you say one thing,
いっぱい色んな反応があるから、荒波ってことね。
you get lots of different reactions, so it's like rough seas.
そうそうそう。
Right, right, right.
うんうん。
Yep, yep.
それでは、正解を発表します。
And now, I'll announce the correct answer.
お！
Oh!
スバルにとってインターネットとは、
To Subaru, the internet is...
ずばり、宇宙です！
in a word... space!
全員不正解です。
Everyone is wrong.
宇宙！宇宙か！
Space! Space, huh?
宇宙か！
It's space?
宇宙だろ、普通に。
Of course it's space.
でもさ、宇宙って光と闇じゃね？
But isn't space just light and dark?
いやいや、そんなでかすぎんだろ、規模が。
No, no, that's way too big of a scale.
こじつけやめて、無理やりすぎる。
Stop forcing it. That's too much of a stretch.
勝てないですよ。バツバツ、はい。
You can't win this. Wrong, wrong. Yes.
まあ簡単に言うと何で宇宙かって言うと、
Well, to put it simply, why space?
まあまずとんでもなく広くて、未知のもので、
First off, it's incredibly vast and unknown,
で、かつなんかそのカオス感とか
and also the feeling of chaos,
あと自分じゃどうしようもできない感じが
and how things are beyond my control,
宇宙って感じです。はい。
that feels like space. Yes.
大丈夫ですか？なるほどねー。
Is that okay? I see...
なるほどな。そういうことなんだ。よかったね。
I see. So that's what it is. Good for you.
よかったねってなんやねん。
What do you mean, "good for you"?
じゃあ、ひいきめに。はい、載せといてください。
Okay, just to be generous... Yes, please put it up.
はい。うーん。
Yes. Hmm.
それではここで、えー、じゃあちょっとシチュエーション問題いっちゃおうかな。
Alright, at this point, uh, let's move on to a situational question.
やばい。シチュエーション問題。
Oh no. A situational question.
マジかよ。稼げんかった。やだ。
Seriously? I couldn't earn points. No way.
シチュエーション問題行くよ。
We're doing a situational question.
シチュエーション問題は、じゃあ…
The situational question is, well...
え、じゃあみおしゃ、1か2で好きな方選んで。
Okay, Mio-sha, pick the one you like, 1 or 2.
え？1か2で？
Huh? 1 or 2?
じゃあ… 1で。
Then... I'll pick 1.
1。それでは1のシチュエーションはまずはこちらです。
One. Alright, the first situation is this one.
今から皆さんに
From now, all of you
待ち合わせに20分遅れてきた時のスバルのセリフを言ってもらいます。
will say a line Subaru would use when she's 20 mins late.
無理です、知らんマジで。
No way, I have no idea, seriously.
え、でもこれ、いつものじゃない？
But isn't this her usual thing?
いや、そう、これ、いつもとか言うな。
Hey, don't say "usual."
いやいや、いつも20分遅れてるわけじゃないからね。
No, no, I'm not always 20 minutes late, you know.
俺知らねえよ、待ち合わせしてねえんだよ、こっちは。
I wouldn't know. We've never met up!
何で遅れてきたの？遊ぶ約束？
Why was she late? A playdate?
遊ぶ約束かな。遊ぶ方向で。
I guess a playdate. Let's go with that.
はい、遊ぶ約束です。
Yes, it's a playdate.
じゃあ、我こそはっていう人いますか？
So, is there anyone who wants to go first?
え、これ書かなくていいってこと？
Huh, so we don't have to write it?
あ、これ書かなくていい。あの、みんな
Ah, you don't have to write this. Um, everyone
やってもらう、ここで。
will have to do it, right here.
全員やんの？全員やります。
Everyone's doing it? Everyone will do it.
大空スバルの真似してください。
Please imitate Oozora Subaru.
全員これやるんだ。あれじゃん、前にやった人の
We're all doing this? Oh, right. The person who went before
参考にしてれば。
can be a reference.
あ、じゃあ僕行こうかなあ。
Ah, then maybe I'll go.
おお！え、え、え、え、え、え。
Oh! Hey, hey, hey, hey.
解像度高いんじゃない？じゃあ。
You must have a clear idea, then.
猫又さん行きますか？
Nekomata-san, will you go?
はい、行きます。
Yes, I'll go.
じゃあ、猫又さん、待ち合わせに20分遅れてきた時のスバルのセリフ、どうぞ。
Alright, Nekomata-san. Subaru's line for being 20 mins late. Go.
はあ、はあ。まじごべーん！
*pants, pants* I'm SOOO sorry!
いや、家出る前まではさ、間に合うかなと思ったんだけど、
Well, before I left home, I thought I'd make it, but...
いや、ギリ間に合わなかったから。最近遅刻してなかったんだけどね。
I just barely didn't. I haven't been late recently, though.
いやマジごめん。あの今日焼肉
I'm really sorry. Um, today, for yakiniku,
おごります！
it's my treat!
まんまやんそれ。
That's exactly her.
なるほどね。はいはいはいはい。
I see. Right, right, right, right.
じゃあ、続いて
Okay, next...
続いて誰か行きますか？
Who wants to go next?
ちょっと待って。回答じゃないのこれ。
Wait a sec. Isn't that the right answer?
同じじゃん。これみんな同じになる。
It's the same. Everyone's gonna say the same thing.
完璧だったけどね、普通に。
It was perfect, though.
まあ、まあ言ってみるかみたいな感じか。まあまあ言ってみて、言ってみて。
Well, let's just say it and see. Yeah, just say it.
言ってみて一回。うん、一旦、一旦。
Go on, just say it. Yeah, for now.
じゃあ、続いてる人。
Okay, next person.
あ、じゃあトワトワトワ。トワ？
Okay, Towa-towa-towa. Towa?
おお。じゃあトワさんね。じゃあ、トワの
Ooh. Okay, Towa-san. So, Towa's guess for...
えー、スバルが、スバルが待ち合わせ20分遅れてきた時のセリフです。お願いします。
what Subaru would say if she were 20 minutes late. Please begin.
マジでごめん。本当にごめん。いやでも、
I'm so sorry! I'm really sorry! But, you know,
あれだったのね、ちょっと急にお腹が痛くなっちゃって。
my stomach suddenly started hurting.
うそ、うそ、うそ。これ！お腹の痛みを理由にする。
Lies, lies, lies! This! Using a stomachache as an excuse.
謝って一応。なるほどね。
While still apologizing. I see.
ちょっと、まあ、一旦何も言わんとくわ、ここでは。一旦何も言わん。
Okay, I won't say anything for now. Not a word.
ノーヒントだ。
No hints.
はい、じゃあ続いて、じゃあこれ、次みこち行く？
Okay, next! Miko-chi, you wanna go?
はい！
Yes!
はい。じゃあみこちの
Okay. So, Miko-chi's...
えー、20分遅れてきた時のセリフです。どうぞ。
line for being 20 minutes late. Go!
あー、ごめーん！
Ah, I'm sooorry!
いやー、もう本当にごめん！マジでごめん！
Seriously, I'm really sorry! I really am!
いや、今日絶対焼肉奢るから！
Look, I'll definitely treat you to yakiniku today!
奢る！待って待って。
A treat! Wait, wait.
同じじゃん。
It's the same!
かわいいじゃん！え、そのワンピースめっちゃかわいいじゃん！
So cute! Hey, that dress is super cute!
機嫌取ってる機嫌。
You're trying to butter me up.
言う言う。
She'd say that.
ああ、なるほどね。
I see, I see.
ほぼおかゆと一緒です。
It's almost the same as Okayu's.
焼肉奢りからの、相手の服を褒めていくっていう
Offering yakiniku, then praising their clothes.
でもみこちゃんとすばちゃんは似たもの同士だから、
But Miko-chan and Suba-chan are like two peas in a pod,
はいはい。
Right, right.
あの、謝るのはあっても、言い訳することはあんまないなって。
so she'd apologize, but I don't think she'd make excuses.
みこちゃんには別に言い訳しなくていいかみたいな
Like, "I don't need to make excuses for Miko-chan."
そうなんだ。
So that's how it is.
なるほどね、なるほどね。
I see, I see.
ああ、人によってちゃんとね、対応変えていくタイプね。
So she changes her response depending on the person.
じゃあ続いて、じゃあマーちゃん行っとく？この辺で。
Okay, next! Ma-chan, wanna go now?
超マジ分からん。分からん。
I seriously have no idea. I don't know.
待ち合わせしたことなさすぎて。
We've never met up, so...
最後よりいいでしょ？はい、じゃあマーちゃん行こう。
It's better than going last, right? Okay, Ma-chan, go.
それじゃマーちゃんによるスバルが20分遅れてきた時のセリフです。どうぞ。
Here's Ma-chan's guess for what Subaru would say. Go!
うん。ごめん、マーちゃん、遅れちゃった。
Yeah. Sorry, Ma-chan, I'm late.
なんで食ってんの？
Why are you eating?
なんで食ってんの？食ってんの？こいつ。
Why are you eating? Are you eating?
プーさん。
Winnie the Pooh.
あ、ちょっとさ、スバルさ、ちょっと腹痛くてさ、
Uh, hey, Subaru, my stomach hurt so bad,
ディストピアかと思ったわ、マジで。
I thought it was dystopia.
ディストピア？
Dystopia?
え？
Huh?
ちょっとごめん、腹痛くてさ。あ、もう大丈夫、なんともない。
Sorry, my stomach hurt. Oh, I'm fine now. It's nothing.
大丈夫だから。あ、焼肉奢ります。
It's okay. I'll treat you to yakiniku.
焼肉！
Yakiniku!
やっぱ焼肉なんだ。焼肉に収穫するんだね。
So it is yakiniku. It all comes down to yakiniku, huh?
でもマリンの中ではもっとテンション低く、
But in Marine's mind, it's more low-energy,
スバル先輩マリンに対して「ごめーん！」って感じじゃ来ないんだもん。
Subaru-senpai wouldn't come to me all high-energy like "Sooorry!"
ああ、そっか。
Oh, really?
そうなんだ。「ごめんマーちゃん」って感じのテンションの低さ。
That's right. It'd be low-energy, like "Sorry, Ma-chan."
そうなんだ。マリンに対してはそういう感じなんだ。
I see. So that's how she is with you.
あ、まあ、今に、今、まだ言いませんね、何も。
Well, for now... I won't say anything yet.
そうですね、そうですね。はいはいはい。
Right, right.
じゃあミオしゃの、ミオしゃ準備いい？
Okay, Mio-sha... Mio-sha, are you ready?
あ、そうですね。みんながちょっとテンション高めのごめんだったので、
Ah, yes. Everyone's "sorry" was pretty high-energy,
ちょっと別バージョンで行こうかと思います。
so I think I'll go with a different version.
じゃあみおしゃの、えー、スバルが20分遅れてきた時のセリフです。どうぞ。
Alright, here's Mio-sha with what she'd say if Subaru was 20 minutes late. Go ahead.
いや本当に…ごめんみんな。マジでさ…
No, really... I'm sorry, everyone. Seriously...
いやー、間に合うと思ったんだけどなー。
Man, I thought I was going to make it on time...
いや、本当ごめん、本当。うー、でも、あのね
No, I'm really sorry. For real. Umm, but, you know...
でも大丈夫だった。あー。よかったよかった。
...it turned out okay. Ahh. I'm glad, I'm glad.
ま、じゃギリギリセーフってことで。
Well then, let's just say I was barely safe.
自分をフォローしている。
She's trying to cover for herself.
最低だな。
That's the worst.
めちゃめちゃ自分をフォローしてる。
She's really trying to cover for herself.
ちょっと待って、ギリギリ…でも、まあ確かに…
Wait a minute, "barely"? But, well, it's true...
スバルちゃんの中では10分は遅れていいけど、20分はダメっていう多分
In Subaru-chan's mind, 10 minutes late is okay, but 20 minutes is not.
気持ちがあるからもっと謝るかもね。
So she'd probably apologize more.
うん、すいません、すいませんっていう感じでね。
Yeah, something like "I'm sorry, I'm sorry."
それはわかるかも。
I can see that.
すいません。
I'm sorry.
はい、それではこの中で正解、一番スバルがいいそうだなーって思った人発表します。
Right, so, out of all these, I'll announce the person who I thought sounded most like me.
お願いします。
Please do.
一番スバルがいいそうなと思った人は…猫又さんです！
The person who I thought sounded most like me... is Nekomata-san!
お前か！
It's you!
やらかしすぎる。
You messed up too much.
やはりそうか。
I knew it.
ま、みんな同じような感じになったけどね。
Well, everyone's was kind of similar.
ミオしゃんも一緒じゃん。
Mio-sha's was the same, too.
ミオしゃん言ってたけど、ただスバル20分も遅刻したらさすがにちょっと言い訳する。
Mio-sha said it, but if I was 20 minutes late, I'd at least make some excuses.
さすがに。
At least.
言い訳で、ごめんなさい、なぜならこういう理由があって遅れたんです、すいませんって言うでしょう。
With excuses, like, "I'm sorry, I was late for this reason, my apologies!"
で、さらに焼肉奢りはマストでやるね。
And on top of that, treating everyone to yakiniku is a must.
あー焼肉は奢る。
Ah, she'd treat us to yakiniku.
一旦奢るんだ。
She'd treat us for now.
はい、なので…でも全体的にすごいみんなリアルで、本当になんか謎の汗が止まらなくて今。
Yes, so... But everyone was so realistic, I can't stop this mysterious sweat right now.
なんか、ほんとに、なんかどうしよう…誕生日なのに変な汗ずっとかいてます。
Like, really... It's my birthday, but I've been sweating strangely this whole time.
はい。それじゃあ、猫又さん、10点です。
Right. In that case, Nekomata-san, 10 points.
すごいなー。
Amazing.
すごい。
いや、強いね。じゃあ、続いて…
Man, you're good. Alright, next...
じゃあ次ちょっと一回クイズ問題に戻ろうかな。
Let's go back to a quiz question for a bit.
おー。
Ooh.
それでは、じゃあ、これ。
Alright then, here it is.
スバルが一番苦手な家事はなんでしょうか？
What household chore is Subaru worst at?
あ、家事？
Oh, a chore?
えええ？
Whaaat?
スバルが一番苦手な家事は？
What chore is Subaru worst at?
えー、でも…細かくするってこと？
Uh, but... do you mean like, specific things?
えー、スバル、そうですね、細かく書けるなら書いてって感じ。
Uhh, Subaru... yeah, if you can write it in detail, please do.
なるほどー。
I see.
えーなんだろ。
Hmm, what could it be?
スバルが一番苦手な家事。
Subaru's worst chore.
うーん。
Hmmm.
これ2択だ と思うけどな
I think it's one of two choices.
でもどっちかなんだよなー、どっちだろう。
But I wonder which one it is.
あー、でもなんかこれは…さあ
Ahh, but this one... well...
スバルが一番苦手な家事ですね。
Subaru's worst chore.
じゃなんかこれなんだけど
Well, I think it's this.
ちょっと細かすぎるからちょっとこう
But it's too specific, so I'll put it like this.
いやこれ！これだ！行けー！
No, this one! This is it! Go!
点数欲しい！点数欲しい！
I want the points! I want the points!
声、声、声
The voice, the voice, the voice...
なるのか
what will it be?
ちょっと待って、なんか書けなくなっちゃった
Wait, I can't write anymore.
書けなくなっちゃった 壊れちゃった
I can't write anymore. It broke.
あ、書き始めたよ
Oh, she started writing.
大丈夫？
Are you okay?
さあ、スバルが一番ね、色々家事と言ってもありますけれども、一番苦手な
Now then, there are many chores, but what is Subaru's least favorite?
うん。
Yes.
でもスバルも自覚ある。これマジで一番苦手だなって
But Subaru herself knows it. "This is seriously my least favorite."
え、なんか唯一、家行ってすごい印象に残ってたことがあるんだよな
Well, there's one thing that really left an impression on me when I went to her house.
これマジかみたいに思った
I was like, "Is this for real?"
ああ、なるほどね
Ah, I see.
いやこれかなあ
I wonder if it's this.
え、家事ってさあ うん、待って
Well, chores are... yeah, wait.
これ苦手だわってめっちゃ思うことあるね。
I do really think, "I'm bad at this."
まあ苦手、基本家事苦手なんだけど、そん中でも一番苦手なやつ。
Well, I'm bad at chores in general, but among them, the one I'm worst at.
ええ
Eeh.
はい
Okay.
じゃあ、えー、それではまず、自信、なんか誰から行きたいとかあります？
Okay, so, first, who's confident and wants to go first?
えー、じゃあうちから行こうかな
Ehh, maybe I'll go first.
じゃあみおしゃ！
Okay, Miosha!
みおしゃの回答はこちらになります、どうぞ！
Miosha's answer is... here it is! Go ahead!
はい、えー、茶碗を洗うこと
Yes, um, washing the bowls.
な、なぜ茶碗洗うと思ったんですか？
Wh-why did you think washing bowls?
え、茶碗を洗ってるとこ見たことない。
Well, I've never seen her wash bowls.
（笑い）そうなんだ
(Laughter) Is that so.
ちょっと待って。なあなあなあ、一回何も言わないで置くか。じゃあ、続いて
Wait a minute. Hey, hey, hey, let's not say anything for a moment. Okay, next up.
じゃあ、次、まあちゃん行くか
Okay, next, shall we go with Maa-chan?
はい
Yes.
はい、じゃあまあちゃんの回答こちらです。どうぞ。
Okay, here's Maa-chan's answer. Go ahead.
掃除。洗濯物が特に片付かん。
Cleaning. Especially not putting away the laundry.
その理由は？
And the reason is?
なんか部屋が全体的に散らかってたのはそうなんだけど、
Her room was generally messy, that's true,
特に一番思ったのが部屋の一角になんか一畳分ぐらい使って洗濯物がどーんって置いてあって、まああって思ったの。
but what I noticed most was a pile of laundry the size of a tatami mat in the corner. I was like, "wow".
こんなことある？って思って。それがめっちゃ印象に残ってて。
I was like, "can this really happen?". That left a huge impression on me.
なんだろ、こんな女性いるんだって思って、これかなと思いました。
I thought, "wow, a woman like this exists," so I figured it was this.
お前ふざけんなよ！こんな女性って
Don't mess with me! "A woman like this..."
主語でかい、主語でかいぞ！
That's a generalization! That's a generalization!
なに、俺にも刺さる
What, that hits me too.
はい これ、ごめん、ちょっと、フォローしといてね、まあちゃんフォロー
Yes. Hey, sorry, please follow up, Maa-chan, follow up.
すいません
Sorry.
これトワ船長と近いというか一緒だわ
This is close to Captain Towa's, or rather, it's the same.
じゃあトワの回答行きましょう。トワの回答こちらです。どうぞ。
Okay, let's go with Towa's answer. Here is Towa's answer. Go ahead.
こちら、あ、ちょっと細かくすぎたかなと思って上に置き書いちゃったけど、下の洗濯物をたたむ。
This one, ah, I thought it was too specific so I wrote on top, but the one below, "folding laundry".
はい！これやっぱりそうだと思わない？ あーあ
Yes! Don't you think this is it? Aah.
その理由は？
And the reason?
トワが畳んでるもん。
Towa always folds it.
そうだよ、いつもトワが畳んでる。
That's right, Towa always folds it.
（笑い）畳ませてんのかよ
(Laughter) You make her fold it?!
その回答も開けてもらっていいですか。じゃあ、猫又さんの回答こちらです。
Can you reveal that answer too? Okay, here's Nekomata-san's answer.
はい、洗濯物を畳む。トワがいつも畳んでいる。
Yes, folding laundry. Towa always folds it.
おー、やばい、一緒なんですけど。
Whoa, that's crazy, it's the same.
おかゆもそう思ってるの？
Okayu thinks so too?
うん、よく見かけますね。
Yes, I see it often.
そうですね。
That's right.
じゃあそして、みこちはちょっと違う回答です。みこちの回答こちらです。どうぞ。
And then, Mikochi has a slightly different answer. Here's Mikochi's answer. Go ahead.
健康なご飯を作る。
Making healthy meals.
確か作ってもらってる。
True, she has others make them for her.
ああ。
Ah.
なんでそう思ったんですか？
Why did you think so?
え、スバちゃんがなんか作ってるとこ見たことないなあって思って。
Well, I thought, I've never seen Suba-chan make anything.
確かにマジでみおん家本当最高とか言って一緒にご飯食ってるイメージしかない。
True, my only image is her saying "Mio's house is the best" and eating with her.
もらって食べてる。
She gets food and eats it.
みおん家来ると飯食えるんだよな。
When I come to Mio's place, I can get a meal.
そうそうそうそう。なんか作ってるとこ全く想像できないなと思って。
Right, right, right, right. I just can't imagine her cooking anything at all.
なるほどね。
I see.
まあ、じゃあ皆さん色々あると思いますけど、回答言っていいですか？
Well everyone, I'm sure you have a lot of answers, but can I reveal it?
はい。はい。
Yes. Yes.
はい。では、スバルが一番苦手な家事を発表します。それは
Yes. Now, I'll announce the chore Subaru is worst at. It's
洗濯物をたたむことです！
Folding laundry!
どっち？え、マリンも！ああ！
Which one? Marine, you too?! Ah!
おかゆ正解！
Okayu, correct!
よっしゃ！
Yes!
そうだね。もう本当に苦手で、
That's right. I'm really bad at it.
まあ、トワがいつもたたんでくれてるのは、そうです。
So, the fact that Towa always folds it for me... that's right.
間違いない。
No doubt about it.
でしょう？
Right?
たたまさせてる。
I'm making her fold it.
先日もたたんで
You folded mine the other day...
ちょっと
Hey...
でも
But...
これだけは言わせて、本当に、トワ本当にいつもありがとうなんだけど
Let me just say this, Towa, thank you so much always, but...
いや、トワはね、なんかね、
You see, Towa just...
なんか気が付いたらたたんでくれてんだって。
When I notice, she's already folded it for me.
ええー！
No way!
確かに喋りながらたたんでる。
She does fold it while talking.
喋りながらたたんでる。
Folds it while talking.
ええ！
Wow!
たたんでくれてるの。
She folds it for me.
え、でも、うちもこの間たたんだよ。
But I folded it the other day too!
みんなもたたんでくれた。
Everyone folded it for me.
めっちゃたたんでるやん。
Everyone's folding so much.
でも、そうだよね。あんなドーンって置いてあったらたたまなきゃってなるよね。
But yeah. If it's just piled up there, you feel like you have to fold it.
そう、そうなのよね。
Yeah, that's true.
あそこにあると、なんかもう口と手両方動かした方が
When it's there, I feel like I should use both my mouth and hands...
いいんじゃないかと思ってやっちゃうんだよな。
so I just do it.
確かに。
True.
まあ、そうですね。まあ洗濯物たたむのが苦手で。
Well, yes. I'm bad at folding laundry.
ちなみに茶碗を洗うのは、あの、見たことないと思いますけど、
By the way, about washing dishes... you've probably never seen it,
見えないとこでこっそり洗ってます。
but I do wash them secretly where you can't see.
で、
And...
スバルはホロライブ入る前、わりと自炊してましたということで。
Before I joined Hololive, I used to cook for myself quite a bit.
おおー！
Oh!
すごい！すごい！
Amazing! Amazing!
うん、トワと、えー、おかゆと、マリンが正解10ポイントです！
Yes, Towa, Okayu, and Marine are correct for 10 points!
イエーイ！
Yay!
わー！
Wow!
まあ、まずい、うちだけ0ポイントじゃん。
Oh no, I'm the only one with 0 points.
さあ。
Now...
1億ポイントだから、大丈夫かな。
There are 100 million points, so it should be fine.
ああ、じゃあ、まあまあ、わかる。
Ah, well, I see.
どうせ。
It's inevitable.
まあまあ、一旦さあ、ど、そこまで読んでる？
Wait, are you thinking that far ahead?
どうせやめてね。
Don't say it's inevitable.
今これ、裏でさ、マネちゃんがカウントしてるから、
Right now, my manager is counting behind the scenes,
今、「えっ、1億ポイント！？」とかで、もう今、冷や汗止まらんと思うから。
so if she hears "What? 100 million points?!", she'll be sweating bullets.
マネちゃん、どうせ最後1億ポイントだから。
My manager knows the last one is worth 100 million points anyway.
いや、ないから。じゃあ、ちょっと、続けて問題行きますよ。
No, there isn't. Okay, let's move on to the next question.
次の問題は、ちょっと変わった問題です。
The next question is a bit different.
今から、えー、前回ね、チュキチュキ選手権に参加してくれたメンバーですね。
Now, these are the members who participated in the last "Chukichuki Championship".
えー、わため、えー、すぅ、えー、そしてノエル、の3人に
Watame, Suu, and Noel, the three of them...
スバルになりきって、スバ友への感謝のメッセージを書いてもらいました。
pretended to be Subaru and wrote a message of gratitude to the Subatomo.
今から手紙が4つ出ます。その中に、本当にスバルの書いた手紙は1枚だけあります。
Four letters will appear. Among them, only one was actually written by Subaru.
さあ、どれでしょう？という問題です。それではお手紙こちらです。
The question is, which one is it? Here are the letters.
おおー。
Oh.
これ、画面見えてます？今。
Can you see the screen?
見えてる。
I can see it.
はい。
Yes.
おおー、なんか、はいはいはい。
Oh, okay, I see.
あの、1個だけスバルがガチでスバ友に宛てた手紙があります。どれでしょう？
Only one of these is a letter Subaru genuinely wrote to her Subatomo. Which is it?
ちょっと面白すぎない？これ。
Isn't this too funny?
じゃあ、1番から読んでいくか。1番から。
Okay, let's read from number one.
じゃあ、読み上げてください。お願い、読み上げて。お願いします。
Please read it aloud. Please, read it.
じゃあ、読んでいきますよ。まず、
Okay, I'll read it. First...
1番の問題は、これかな？
The first one is this one, right?
スバ友のみんなへ。いつもいっぱいの応援ありがとう。
To all my Subatomo. Thank you for all your support.
今年もお誕生日迎えられて嬉しいしゅば！！！
I'm happy to celebrate my birthday again this year, shuba!!!
嬉しいシュバ。
I'm so happy! Shuba!
これからも思い出いっぱい作ろうね！
Let's make lots of memories together!
大好きシュバ～！大空スバル。
I love you, shuba! Oozora Subaru.
うーん。うーん。うーん、うーん、うん。
Mmm. Mmm. Mmm-hmm.
じゃ、2番の問題、え、2番の、えー、やつはこちらです。
Okay, question number two. Here is the second option.
スバ友の皆。今日はスバルの誕生日だー！
To all Subatomo. Today is Subaru's birthday!
ぶっちゃけ実感なくて草！
Honestly, it doesn't feel real, lol.
でもスバ友の皆がお祝いしてくれて、実感わいてきた。
But with you all celebrating with me, it's starting to feel real.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
梅雨も明けたし、スバルの誕生日だし夏が来たな！
The rainy season is over, it's Subaru's birthday, so summer is here!
みんなで海行くシュバーーー！！！
Let's all go to the beach, shubaaaa!
じゃ、続いて。ああー。3番です。
Okay, next. Aww. It's number 3.
ちわーす！大空スバルです！
Yo! It's Oozora Subaru!
お誕生日！みんなは元気ですか？スバルは元気です！
Happy birthday! How is everyone? Subaru's doing great!
今年も、素敵な誕生日をみんなと迎えることが出来て嬉しいです！
I'm so happy to celebrate a wonderful birthday with you all again this year.
いっぱいの応援と元気をいつもありがとう！
Thank you always for all your support and energy!
スバルは配信してスバ友と遊ぶ時間、みんなと過ごす時間が楽しい！
The time I spend streaming and playing with my Subatomo, it's so much fun!
みんなともっと楽しいことを一緒に出来るように頑張るぞー！
I'll do my best so we can do even more fun things together!
今年もよろしくねー！
Let's have a great year!
じゃ、続いて。うーん、うーん、うーん。え、4番です。
Okay, next. Mmm, mmm, mmm. Uh, number 4.
スバ友の皆へ。ちわーす！
To all my Subatomo. Yo!
ホロライブ2期生大空スバルです！
It's Hololive 2nd Gen, Oozora Subaru!
今日はスバルの誕生日！
Today is Subaru's birthday!
今年も君と一緒に過ごせてスバルは幸せです！
I'm so happy to spend it with you again this year, Subaru is so happy!
本当にいつも応援ありがとう！！！
Thank you so much for your support!
これからも一緒に、最強で最高な毎日を過ごそう！
Let's continue to have the strongest and best days together!
大好きだ！大空スバル。
I love you! Oozora Subaru.
さあ、どれでしょう？
So, which one is it?
ええー！
Ehh?!
これ書くやつ？これ書いてください。
Is this the one we have to write?
1から4まででね。
From one to four.
じゃ、2択なんだよな。
So it's a two-choice question.
これでもね、むずいよ。
But you know, this is difficult.
むずい？
Difficult?
うん、結構みんなすごいなと思った。
Yeah, I thought everyone did a great job.
てか、なんなんだ？
So, which one was it?
いや、これ書いたことあるわ。
I mean, if anything, I've written this before.
全然、文章違う。全然ある、マジで。
The text is completely different, but... it's all different.
ええー。
Ehh?
だって、みんなさ、ビックリマークいっぱいついてるもんね。
Because everyone has a lot of exclamation points.
ちょっとビックリマーク式クイズやめてね、ビックリマーク式クイズ。
Stop with the exclamation mark guessing!
はい。
Okay.
このスバル部分がひらがななのか、カタカナなのかというところにも何かヒントが。
Is the "Subaru" part in hiragana or katakana? There might be a hint there.
ああ、なるほどね。はいはいはい。大空スバル、スバル、すごい。
Oh, right. Oozora Subaru. Subaru. Yeah.
ちなみに書いたのは、えー、すう、ノエル、わためが書いてくれました。
By the way, the ones who wrote them were Su, Noel, and Watame.
ほお、なるほど。なるほど。
Oh, I see. I see.
はい。それでは、書き終わりましたか？
Okay. So, have you all finished writing?
はい。はい。はい。
Yes. Yes. Yes.
それでは、じゃあ、まず、えー、どうしようかな、誰か、じゃあ、みおしゃから行っとくか。
Okay, then, first, what should we do? Should we start with Miosha?
一斉に出せばいいんじゃない？じゃあ、ラストだ。確かに。
Shouldn't we just show them all at once? The last one, right? Okay.
はい。じゃあ、一斉に出しちゃうよ。それでは、こちら、ドン！
Okay. Let's all show them at once. Here they are! Bam!
それじゃあ、まずは、みおしゃ、理由を教えてください。
Okay, first up, Miosha, tell us your reasoning.
はい。え、4番です。
Yes. Uh, it's number 4.
はい。えっと、たぶん、みんな、あの、他の人、なんか、トワのすごい、1番めちゃくちゃ癖強いな。
Yes. Um, I think everyone else... Towa's #1 is really unique.
確かに。
Right?
何これ？
What is that?
飾り付け、何なん、それ？
What is that decoration?
先、先、黒い。ああ、びっくりした。全部黒いのね。はいはいはいはいはい。
The tip is black... Oh, I see. It's all black. Okay, okay, okay.
えっと、あのですね、みんなね、あの、依頼されて、色々ね、気を付けると思うんですよ。
Um, when everyone was asked to write it, I think they'd be careful about things.
はいはい。大空スバルのスバルはカタカナにしなきゃとか。
Like, making sure to write "Subaru" from "Oozora Subaru" in katakana.
うんうんうん。
Mhm.
でも、4番だけ、一番最後にひらがなになっている。
But only number 4 is written in hiragana at the very end.
みおち、みおち、1番もひらがなですよ。1番もだよ。
Mio-chi, Mio-chi, number one is also in hiragana. Number one is too!
え、本当だ！
Eh, you're right!
ぽんじゃだ！
It was a flub!
さあ、もう回答は、交換できませんよ。
Okay, you can't change your answers anymore.
回答は変えれませんよ。回答は、もう出しちゃったからね。
You can't change them. You've already submitted them.
まあ、でも4かなって思った。
Well, but I did think it might be 4.
4かなってね。
That it might be 4.
ビックリマークめっちゃあるし。
It has a ton of exclamation marks.
じゃあ続いて、
Alright, next up,
えー、3番を選んだ猫又さん。どうして3番だと思ったんですか？
Okayu-san, you chose #3. Why did you think it was #3?
うーん、難しいんだけど。
Hmm, it's difficult but...
はいはい。
I see.
ま、消去法かなあ。
Well, maybe by process of elimination.
ええー。
Ohh.
消去法ね。
Process of elimination, huh?
消去法。
Process of elimination.
なんで4番とかさ、他は違うと思ったの？2とか1とか。
Why did you think the others, like 4, 2, or 1, were wrong?
ま、ええ、これむずいな。違うと思ってた本人だったらマジで申し訳ないんだが、
Well, hmm, this is tricky. If I'm wrong and it is her, I'd feel bad, but...
はいはい。
Right.
え、4は、まず、
Um, for number 4, first...
うん。
Yeah.
うーん、こんなにびっくりマークはつけないかなあっていう。
Hmm, I don't think she'd use this many exclamation marks.
ああ、なるほどね。ああ、そうだな。
Ah, I see. Yeah, that's true.
わかるわかる。
I get it, I get it.
そうで、
And so...
1番は、大好きしゅば～って言うかなあ。
for number 1, I wonder if she'd say 'Daisuki shuba~'.
ええ？言わないよ。言わない。わかるわ。
Huh? She wouldn't. She wouldn't. I get it.
言わないと思う。全然言いそうなんだけど、
I don't think so. It sounds like her, but...
どうかなあって思ったのと、はいはい。
I wondered about that, and...
ま、2はこれは完全に、あの、文章のスバルちゃんじゃなくて、口上のスバルちゃんだなと思って。
Well, number 2 is totally not written Subaru, but spoken Subaru.
なるほど。
I see.
そう。うーん、まあ1か3かなで、うん。
Right. Hmm, so I thought it was either 1 or 3, yeah.
ま、誕生日なんでちょっと真面目に書くかなということで3にしました。
Since it's her birthday, I thought she might write more seriously, so I chose 3.
なるほどね。なるほど。
I see. I see.
じゃあ、続いて、1番を選んだ人多いですけど、まーちゃん、なんで1番だと思ったんですか？
Okay, next, many chose #1. Maa-chan, why did you think it was #1?
ええ、なんか、こんなに一生懸命いっぱい書かないかなと思って。
Umm, well, I didn't think she'd write so much with so much effort.
まあ、1番くらいの分量かなと思って。
The length of #1 seemed about right.
だけど知らん。わかんないけど、たぶんそう。
But I don't know. I'm not sure, but probably.
なるほどね。まあ、番組のことを考えて、そこまでね、さらっと書くんじゃないかと。
I see. So for the show, you thought she'd just write something quick.
いうことですね。さらっとね、そうそうそうそう。
That's right. Just something quick, yes, yes, yes.
じゃあ続いて、とわ、なんで1番だと思ったの？
Alright, next, Towa, why did you think it was number 1?
うーん、はい、あ、すいません。
Umm, yes, oh, sorry.
はいはいはい。とわさん、なんで1番だと思ったんですか？
Yes, yes. Towa-san, why did you think it was number 1?
えっとまず、自分で書くから、これ消去法で、
Um, first, since she's writing it herself, by process of elimination...
多分挨拶はしないなって思ったの。だから3を消したんまず。
I thought she probably wouldn't write a greeting. So I eliminated 3 first.
なるほど。
I see.
ああ、スバルってわかってるから、多分言わないなっていうのと、
Ah, since everyone knows it's her, she probably wouldn't say it, and...
で、2番は、絵文字が多すぎるかなって思って、はいはい。
for number 2, I thought there were too many emojis, right, right.
で、スバルちゃん大好きしゅば言わないんじゃないかなって思ったけど、
And I thought she wouldn't say "Subaru-chan daisuki shuba," but...
口頭では言わないだけで、文章では言うんじゃないかな読みで1。
she just wouldn't say it out loud. I figured she'd write it, so I chose 1.
ああ、なるほど。なるほどね。
Ah, I see. I see.
じゃあ最後、さくらみこさん、なんで1だと思ったんすか？
Okay, last, Sakura Miko-san, why did you think it was 1?
え、スバちゃんの、あの、Xの投稿をね、一度検索したことがありまして。
Uh, I once looked up Suba-chan's posts on X.
そうだね。あった、あった。で、そん時感じたのが、こいつ文章少ねえ。
That's right. Right, right. And what I felt then was, "This girl's sentences are short."
しかも、すごい端的だし、なんかビックリマークとりあえず付けてるって思って、
And they're very concise, and it feels like she just adds exclamation marks.
1番、1番がぽいなと思ったんだけど、
So I thought number 1 seemed likely, but...
はいはい。まあ4番とも迷ったんですが、4番はノエルなのではないかと思い、
Right, right. I was also torn with number 4, but I thought 4 might be Noel,
はいはいはいはい。
right, right.
で、2番がノエル、
and number 2 is Noel...
4番が…
Number 4 is...
3番が…
Number 3 is...
4番がわたメ
number 4 is Watame.
なのではみたいな感じで考えました。
That's how I thought about it.
なるほどね。
I see.
なるほど。
それじゃあ全員回答がでそろって理由も言ったということで。
Alright, everyone's answers are in, so...
え、どれだろう、ドキドキ。
I wonder which one it is. My heart's pounding.
発表します。
I'll announce it!
オオゾラ・スバルが書いた手紙は
The letter written by Oozora Subaru...
4番です！
is number 4!
やったー！
Yes!
うわあ！当たった！当たったー！当たった！
You got it right! I got it right! I knew it!
こりゃーしゃーしゃーしゃ！
It's a big deal!
それは、え、まず、え、びっくりマークはこれぐらい普通に付けますで
First of all, I normally use that many exclamation marks,
マジかよ
No way!
マジかよ。絶対スバルのこと考えてるだろ！
No way! You must have written it while thinking of me!
いや、思ってない思ってない。
No, I didn't!
びっくりマークはこれぐらい普通に付けます。
I usually use this many exclamation marks.
で、大好きだわこういう時はちゃんとしっかり伝えます。
And as for 'daisuki da,' I properly say it on occasions like this.
うわー、ずるいなー。
Oh, how cunning!
いや、でも本当にみんなめっちゃクオリティ高くて。
But honestly, everyone's quality was so high.
特に3番、えっとね、言うと1番がわたメ、2番がノエル、3番がスウなんだけど。
Especially number 3... well, 1 is Watame, 2 is Noel, and 3 is Okayu.
まず1番はTwitterに似すぎ、マジで。その、言ったけど。
First, number 1 is too much like my Twitter, seriously. Like I said before.
完全にスバルのTwitterを完全にわたメが模倣してきてて
Watame completely mimicked Subaru's Twitter.
すごいよ。
It's so good!
で、2番もすごいのが、2番ノエルちゃん、スバルが使う絵文字を完全に、あの、模倣してる。
And number 2 is amazing. Noel-chan completely mimicked the emojis Subaru uses.
特に誕生日だのあと
Especially, the one after 'birthday.'
波線をスバルだけが使ってる独特な波線があるんだけど、それを使ってきたんが
This wavy line is a unique one that only Subaru uses, and she used it!
マジで震えた。
I was trembling.
使ってる！これDiscordのモードに溶け込んでんだよな、これ。
She uses it! It's because she's integrated into our Discord mode!
確かに。
That's right!
それで、3番ね。
Then, number 3.
3番はこれスウなんだけど、マジでビビったんが、これスバル、ファン向けにそのメッセージ書くじゃん、あの、グッズに。
Number 3 is from Okayu, but I was so surprised. I've written messages like that for fans, for merch.
そこで1回『元気ですか？ スバルは元気です』みたいなの書いたことあるし
I've written something like, 'Are you well? Subaru is well!' before.
なんかあった記憶するし。
I feel like I remember doing that, and...
で、しかもこの1番最後にさ、あの、みんなともっと楽しいこと一緒に出来るように頑張るぞ！とかも書いた記憶しかない。
And the part at the end, 'Let's do more fun things together, I'll do my best!' I totally remember writing that.
最初に自己紹介入れてんのもマジでスバルすぎて、なんかスバ友を感じた、かなり。
And introducing herself at the beginning is also very Subaru-like, so I felt a real Subaru connection with her.
おお！
Wow!
でもね、こんな中、自己紹介するんだもん。そう、こういう時はね、ちゃんとします。はい。では、みおしゃ
So, in the midst of all this... yes, when it comes to this, I'm very particular. Okay, Mio-sha,
10ポイントです！おめでとう！
10 points! Congratulations!
すごい！
Amazing!
これ、ムズい！これは分からんわ、すごい！
This is so hard. I can't figure it out.
これすごいですね。はい。
This is amazing. Right.
で、え、50分が近づいてきたので、おっと！
So, we're approaching the 50-minute mark... oh!
そろそろ結果発表の前なんですけど、
It's almost time to announce the results, but...
なに？
What is it?
告知タイム、どどどん！
Announcement time! Boom boom boom boom boom!
やった！告知タイムー！
Yay! Announcement time!
いえーい！
Yay!
声、真似のやつ
I'm not gonna do the voice.
はい、それでは早速、今年のグッズ紹介に行きたいと思います。なんと今日のこの後22時から、大空スバル誕生日記念2025のグッズが出ます！
Alright, let's get right to this year's merch announcement. Starting at 22:00 today, the Oozora Subaru Birthday Celebration 2025 merch will be released!
えっと、盛り上がってありがとうございます。
Well, thanks for getting hyped up.
何これ？開けよう？これ。すごくかわいい感じで、
What's this? Let's reveal it. It's super cute.
しぐれうい母ちゃんに描いていただきました。
Shigure Ui-kaachan drew it for me.
まずは、おっぱい！
First up, boobs!
2層アクリルパネルです！
It's a 2-layer acrylic panel!
おー！
Ooh!
うわー！
Wow!
これはですね、2層になっていて、なんと、え、前のね、層を取り外すと、
This is a 2-layer panel, and you can remove the front layer
スバル単体になったりもすることが出来ます。
to display Subaru by herself.
え、脱げるの？
You can take it off?
そう、だから全面でね、スバルを見ることが出来ます。
Yes, so you can see the full view of Subaru.
じゃあ続いて、え、こちら。大集合スマホグリップ。
Next up is this. A big collection smartphone grip.
こちらはスマホにつける、え、グリップになります。
This is a grip you attach to your phone.
かわいい！そう、めっちゃ可愛い。かわいい！
Cute! Yes, it's super cute.
マジかわいいな。
So cute.
かわいい！
Cute!
そうなんです。
That's right.
こちらはですね、スバ友をデザインしていただいた、え、けけ先生に描いていただきました。とても可愛いスマホグリップになっています。
This features Subatomo, designed and drawn by Keke-sensei. It's a very cute phone grip.
ワオ。
Wow.
さあ、そしてついにでるぞ、スバ友ぬいぐるみ、大と小！
And now, finally, the Subatomo plushies, large and small!
やったー！ってことで。きゃー！欲しい！
Yay! So... I want it!
きゃー！かわいい！
Kyaa! Cute!
そう、大と小が出ます。これ両方出る。
Yes, there's a large and a small. Both are being released.
大きい。
Big.
ビッグね、これね。え、こちらなんともちもち素材でね、両方出来上がっていて、
The big one, right. They are both made of a squishy material
え、いいなー。
Oh, nice.
あの、ちゃんとね、あの、みこちとね、あの、一緒に考えた。
and, you know, Miko-chi and I thought of this together.
ビッグの方が若干でかくなっていて、スモールの方が若干小さくなっている、えー、感じになっていて、並べるとすごく可愛いです。
The big one is slightly bigger, and the small one is slightly smaller. They look really cute when you put them side-by-side.
ぜひ皆さんチェックしてみてください。
Please check them out.
これはかわいい。はい、かわいいでしょ。
This is cute. Yes, isn't it cute?
そして、フルセット購入特典ではなんと今年も直筆サインをしていただきます！
And for the full set purchase bonus, I'll be handwriting autographs again this year!
おー！
Ooh!
書きます。
I'll sign it.
うん、させていただきます。日本語がもう、ベロベロベロベロ…
Yes, I'll be signing them. My Japanese is all... *slurs*
ヘヘヘ。
Hehehe.
えー今回はですね、フルセット買っていただくとスバルの直筆サイン、そして、箔押し複製メッセージが入ったポストカードが付いてきますので
This time, if you buy the full set, you'll get a postcard with Subaru's handwritten signature and a hot-stamped replica message,
ぜひフルセットは…え、直筆は？え、じゃあ、全員書いて、付いてくるってこと？
so for the full set... Wait, the handwritten one? So everyone who buys gets one?
当たり前だろうが、夏は全員書くんだ！
Of course! I'll sign all of them for summer!
ということで。うわー！やばいじゃん！
And so... Wow! That's insane!
はい。夏はね、全員書かせてもらいますので、皆さんあの、ごゆっくりとね、この後ね、あ、22時になったら購入してください。
Yes. For summer, I'll sign them all, so everyone, please take your time and purchase after 10 PM.
さあ、そしてですね、なんと今年、このフルセットを買っていただいた方にこちら！
And, what's more, this year, for those who purchase the full set, you get this!
えー、ホロカのですね、えー、大空スバルのこの水着バージョンの、今年のね、ういママが描いてくれたとっても可愛いイラストのカードも付いてきます。
It's a Hololive card of Oozora Subaru in her swimsuit version, with the super cute illustration that Ui-mama drew this year.
これ欲しいんじゃない？みんな。いいなー。いいね。
Don't you all want this? Nice. So good.
こちらね、使用できる、実際にね、使用できますから、ホロカで。はい。
You can actually use this card in the HoloCa game.
かわいい！カードも付いてきて、サインも付いてくんの？
Cute! The card comes with it, and a signature too?
そうなんです！このめちゃめちゃ可愛いね、限定カードぜひ皆さん手に入れてください。
That's right! Everyone, please get your hands on this super cute limited edition card.
以上、大空スバル誕生日記念2025、とっても可愛いね、しぐれうい母ちゃんに描いてもらったイラストとともにお送りしました。
That's all for the Oozora Subaru Birthday Celebration 2025, brought to you with this super cute illustration drawn by Shigure Ui-kaachan.
ちなみにね、これスバ友いるけど、これしぐれうい母ちゃんが描いた初めてのスバ友の
By the way, the Subatomos are here, and this is the first time Shigure Ui-kaachan has drawn
ビッグとスモールになりますので。ええ！かわいい！そうなんだ！
the big and small ones. Ehh! Cute! Is that so!
そうなんです、すごい可愛いのでぜひ皆さんチェックしてみてください。ということで…
That's right, they're super cute, so please check them out. And with that...
それではね、結果発表。
And now, for the results.
発表かな？そろそろ
It's time for the announcement, isn't it?
おお！
Oh!
とか言って、もう結果が見えすいてんだよ
Saying that, but the result is already obvious.
いやいや、わかんないでしょ。何点とるかわからんから
No, no, you don't know. We don't know how many points we'll get.
え、もしかして最後のやつ1億、1億ポイントだったりする？
Wait, maybe the last one is worth 100 million points?
え？
Huh?
急に？
Suddenly?
じゃあ、ちょっと1億ポイントをもう1問だけ行っちゃう？
Alright, should we do one more question for 100 million points?
え！
What!
いっちゃう、いっちゃう、いっちゃう、いっちゃう
Let's do it, let's do it, let's do it, let's do it!
当てれば
If we get it right...
ええー？
Ehhh?
来たー！
Here it comes!
じゃあ最後の問題ね、最後の
Okay, the final question, the last one.
来い来い！
Come on, come on!
これで勝てるぞ、来い来い来い来い！
We can win with this. Come on, come on, come on!
さあ、どれにしようかなー
Now, which one should I pick...
何だ？
What is it?
じゃあ、こちら！最後の総仕上げ！
Alright, this one! The grand finale!
スバルにとっての宝物は？
What is Subaru's treasure?
だ！
It's...
うわー！
Whoa!
なんでしょうか？
What could it be?
さすがに
Of course.
Of course...
うわー！
Whoa!
スバルにとっての
For Subaru...
いや、これはもうさあ
It's this, right...
いや、これだろう
No, it's gotta be this.
え、さすがに
Oh, of course...
マリンちゃん、これ1億ポイントらしいから、ちょっとよろしく！
Marine-chan, this is apparently worth 100 million points, so please!
えええ！
Ehhh!
マリンちゃん、これ1億ポイントです
Marine-chan, this is worth 100 million points.
ええ、悩む。どっちだ？
Ehh, I'm torn. Which is it?
これ1個？
Is it just one thing?
どっちかあるよね
It's one or the other, right?
え？
Huh?
何々？
What is it?
1個？
One thing?
うーん、どう答えるでしょう、スバルは。これをきかれたときに
Hmm, how would Subaru answer when asked this?
うー
Ooh.
あー
Ahhh.
これをきかれた時に、スバルはなんと答えるかを考えたらわかるんじゃないかな
If you think about what Subaru would say when asked this, you might get it.
うわ、え、え、え、えー
Whoa, eh, eh, eh, ehhh.
そう、そうなってくると
Right, when it comes to that...
さあ、なんかそんな単純じゃない気がしてきた
Now... I feel like it's not that simple.
うーん、もうもう、でも単純に行こう
Hmm, no, no, but let's just go with the simple answer.
行こう
Let's go.
さあ、行こう！
Now, let's go!
何個、何個だ？何個なんだ？
How many, how many is it? How many are there?
ええ、ええ！
Eh, eh!
何個なんだ？
How many are there?
ま、ヒントを言うと、1番の宝物ではない
Well, for a hint, it's not the *number one* treasure.
1番の宝物だと1個になっちゃうじゃん
If it were the number one treasure, it'd just be one thing.
あー
Ahhh.
ええ！
Huh!
はい
Yes.
宝物は？だからね
It's "treasures are?", you see.
宝物は？
Treasures are?
ええ？
Huh?
ええ？ええ？
Huh? Huh?
宝物
Treasures...
ええ、ええ？
Huh? Huh?
なんか、匂わせじゃないだろうな
It's not some kind of tease, is it?
ガチでものじゃないだろうな
It's not actually a physical object, right?
ええ？ものなの？
What? Is it an object?
遊戯王カードとかやめろよ
Don't let it be a Yu-Gi-Oh! card.
宝物
Treasure.
そんなわけなかろう
That can't be it.
宝物は？
Treasures are?
ええ？
Huh?
いやいや、さすがにさすがに概念だと思うよ。そんなね、遊戯王カードなわけない
No, no, of course it's a concept. There's no way it's a Yu-Gi-Oh! card.
さすがに物じゃないよね
It's not an object, right?
それでは、これミスリード
Alright, this is a misdirect.
じゃあ、まず誰？誰から？自信ある人いる？
Okay, who's first? Anyone confident?
じゃあ、当てちゃうよ、勝手に
Alright, I'll just pick someone.
うん。はい
Yeah. Yes.
じゃあ、まずはみこちの回答を見ていきましょう。みこちの回答はこちらです。どうぞ！
Okay, first, let's see Miko's answer. Here is Miko's answer. Go ahead!
心の友！
Friends of the heart!
ああ、でもなんか近いかも、近いかも
Oh, but that might be close, might be close.
うーん、同じような感じかも。
Hmm, maybe something similar.
じゃあまあまあまあまあ友、友的な仲間的な
Well, yeah, something like 'friends' or 'companions'.
なんで心の付けたの？
Why did you add 'of the heart'?
え、なんか心友って言いそうだから。
Eh, because she seems like someone who'd say 'soulmate'.
なるほどね。ジャイアン？
I see. Gian?
ジャイアン？
Like Gian?
続いて、えー、じゃあその隣のマリン
Next, uh, let's go to Marine next to her.
マリンの回答こちらです、どうぞ！
Here is Marine's answer, go ahead!
仲間！(かっこ、全部宇宙仲間である)
FRIENDS! (Meaning, we're all friends in the universe.)
誰？誰？みんなだから
Who? Who? Because it's everyone.
仲間でもある。マリンは
They're also my friends. Marine is...
みんな、みんな仲間な前提でみんなを愛してるってことだから
On the premise that everyone is friends, she loves everyone.
地球アンドテラってことよ
So it's 'Earth and Terra'.
ああ、地球アンドテラね。太陽神ね
Ah, Earth and Terra, huh? The Sun Goddess.
伏線回収ね。じゃあ続いて
Foreshadowing paid off. Okay, next up.
じゃあみこち行くか
Okay, let's go with Miko-chi.
はい
Yes.
じゃあみこちの回答こちらです。どうぞ！
Alright, here is Miko-chi's answer. Go ahead!
スバルと出会ってくれた仲間たちシュバー
The friends who met Subaru, shuba!
あ、同じじゃない？同じじゃない？これ
Oh, isn't that the same? Isn't it?
でもみこち的にはこれエモいやの含みが入っていて
But from Miko-chi's perspective, this has an emotional hint.
スバル自身も自分の宝って思ってるんじゃないかなって
I think Subaru herself considers herself a treasure, you know?
おおぞらスバルっていう存在。
The existence known as Oozora Subaru.
あぁー。仲間たちみたな。
Aah. Like, 'friends'.
なるほどね。そういう意味も含んだね、エモ言葉ね。
I see. So it includes that meaning too, an emotional word.
うんうん。エモ言葉。じゃあ、エモ言葉ね。
Yeah, yeah. An emotional word. Okay, an emotional word.
じゃあ続いて、次はじゃあ、トワさん行きますか。
Okay, next up, shall we go to Towa-san?
トワの回答こちらです。どうぞ！
Here is Towa's answer. Go ahead!
スバ友とホロライブのみんなシュバー
SubaTomo and everyone in Hololive, shuba!
おぉ。あー。ま、シンプルイズベストみたいなね。
Ooh. Ah. Well, it's like, simple is best, you know?
やっぱりね。これでしょう。
Right? It has to be this.
あー、なるほどね。じゃあ、さっきのか。続いて
Ah, I see. So, like the last one. Next.
えー、おかいの回答を見てみましょう。こちらです。どうぞ！
Uh, let's see Okayu's answer. Here it is. Go ahead!
スバルに関わってくれるみんなシュバー
Everyone who's involved with Subaru, shuba!
あー。みこちと同じ感じじゃない？
Aah. Isn't it like Miko-chi's?
うん、なるほどね。出会ってくれて感謝みたいなね。
Yeah, I see. Like, 'thank you for meeting me'.
なるほどね。はい。それではスバルの回答を言います。はい。
I see. Yes. Alright, I will announce Subaru's answer. Yes.
スバルにとっての宝物はスバ友と仲間です！
Subaru's treasure is 'SubaTomo and Friends'!
なので、トワ1億点！
So, Towa gets 100 million points!
えええええええええええ！
EHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHHH!
くそー！スバ友！
Damn it! SubaTomo!
そうです。でもなんかおかいとみこちとかなんか言ったことあるなこれと思って見てた
That's right. But I was watching thinking, I've said something like what Okayu and Miko-chi wrote.
なるほどね。そうなんだ
I see. So that's how it is.
そうね。関わってくれるみんなとかよくスバルメッセージカードに書いたりとかしてるわこれ。
Yeah. I often write things like 'everyone involved with me' on message cards.
でも、ま、シンプルにスバ友も大事だし、宝物だし、あとね、ここにいるみんながね、宝物ってことやスバルにとっての。
But, well, simply put, SubaTomo are important, they're a treasure, and also, everyone here is a treasure to Subaru.
わあ。わあ、ありがとう。嬉しい。
Wow... Wow, thank you. I'm so happy.
え、なんかどうしたのこの空気？
Eh, what's with this atmosphere?
エモいじゃないんだよ、エモいじゃない。
It's not 'emotional', it's not 'emotional'.
エモ
Emotional.
なんか別に、なんか白けろと？びっくりした。
It's not like... are you trying to kill the mood? You surprised me.
だってすごい良い。だって。なんで。なんでなんで。
But that's so nice! But! Why? Why, why?
みんなはさ、スバ友って言う意味で書いたの？
Did you guys write it with the meaning of 'SubaTomo'?
そんなマリンだってスバ友も書いてるんですけどここに。スバ友と仲間だろこれも！
But Marine also wrote 'SubaTomo' here. This is 'SubaTomo and Friends' too!
いや、なんか1つじゃない、1つ書かなきゃいけないのかなと思って友達の方にした。
No, I thought I could only write one, so I went with 'friends'.
に黄色ね。
Oh, it's yellow.
わ、空気がない、空気がない！
Whoa, the air is thin, the air is thin!
僕読めないから。
Because I can't read it.
スバルにとっての宝物はスバ友と仲間なんだよ！
For Subaru, her treasure is her Suba-tomo and comrades!
やべー！友とが書きそうってことな。
Oh crap! It's something a friend would write.
すごい、ちょっと待って。ちょっと待って、マネちゃん憑依してくれてるぞ。
Amazing, wait a sec. Wait, Manager-chan is possessed.
やばい。
Oh crap.
これ最後のやつ一億点にしたらマネちゃんの行動が今までの一時間の行動無駄、無駄になるよ全部。
If the last one is 100 million points, everything Manager-chan did for the past hour will be for nothing.
全部無になるよ！
It'll all be for nothing!
それではここでマネちゃんのね、え、表を見てみましょう。
Alright then, let's take a look at Manager-chan's... uhm, chart.
さあ、ちょっと前に皆さん出させていただきますよ。
Okay, I'm going to bring it up in front of you all.
はい。
Yes.
はい、結果こうなっております。ドン！
Okay, here are the results. Boom!
えー、猫又おかゆさん、30点。
Uhm, Nekomata Okayu-san, 30 points.
宝鐘マリンさん10点、大神ミオさん10点。
Houshou Marine-san 10 points, Ookami Mio-san 10 points.
常闇トワ様、1億10点。え、さくらみこさん10点です。
Tokoyami Towa-sama, 100,000,010 points. Uh, Sakura Miko-san 10 points.
しー！
Shhh!
おかゆだろこれは、おかゆだろこれ！
That has to be Okayu, doesn't it? It has to be Okayu!
え、ということで、優勝は…
And so, the winner is...
優勝！
The winner!
優勝は常闇トワさん、1億10点です！
The winner is Tokoyami Towa-san with 100,000,010 points!
お前嬉しいのかそんなんで
Are you happy with that?
おやびん、嬉しいよ
Oyabin, I'm happy.
嬉しいのかこれ
Are you happy with this?
嬉しいよ。っしゃー！
I am happy. Yeah!
おめでとう。
Congratulations.
ちょっと待って、今マネちゃん焦りすぎて表出すんかいってなんかすごい焦ってますけど、この表がね、すごい分かり…
Wait a sec, Manager-chan is panicking so much, like "Are you really showing the chart?", but this chart is really easy to...
ありがとうございます。はい、常闇さん、優勝です。おめでとうございます。
Thank you. Yes, Tokoyami-san, you're the winner. Congratulations.
そんな常闇さんにはね、こちらお渡ししたいと思います。
To Tokoyami-san, I'd like to give you this.
ありがとうございます！
Thank you!
優勝なんでね、やっぱね、お祝いの品がないと。
Since you're the winner, you know, we need a celebratory gift.
え、何！？こちら？お祝いの品？
Eh, what? This? A celebratory gift?
それでは常闇トワさんにだけこちらを授けようと思います。
Well then, I'd like to bestow this only upon Tokoyami Towa-san.
え、ほんとですか？
Eh, really?
はい。
Yes.
お前がスバルになれ！大空スバルキャップ！おめでとう！
You become Subaru! The Oozora Subaru Cap! Congratulations!
似合ってる！お前がスバルになれ！
It suits you! You become Subaru!
え、スバル？今日から？
Eh, Subaru? From today?
そうだよ。
That's right.
頑張るしゅばよ。
I'll do my shuba-best.
トワがスバルです。
Towa is Subaru.
ありがとうしゅばる。お前がスバルになれ。
Thank you shubaru. You become Subaru.
え、じゃあみこちに代表して付けてもらおうかな。
Uhm, shall we have Miko-chi put it on as a representative?
え！
Eh!
じゃあ、参加賞もございます。
Well, we also have participation prizes.
おお！
Oh!
はい。じゃあ参加賞全員にあげますからね。こちらです。
Yes. Okay, I'll give a participation prize to everyone. Here it is.
お前が今日からスバ友だ！スバ友キャップ！
You're a Subatomo from today! The Subatomo Cap!
かわいい！まじかわいい！
Cute! Seriously cute!
可愛い！似合ってるよみこちに。
Cute! It suits you, Miko-chi.
これ全員あげるんで、ビッグになれるのでね、皆さんあの、使うタイミングあったらぜひ使ってください。
I'm giving this to everyone, you can become big with it, so please use it when you have the chance.
はい。
Yes.
スバルちゃんありがとう。
Subaru-chan, thank you.
スバルちゃん。スバルちゃん。なりきってる？当てる子当てる子
Subaru-chan. Subaru-chan. Are you getting into character? The one who guesses, guesses.
なりきってる。
Getting into character.
なんか低いな声。
Her voice is kind of low.
うん、でもすごいなんか…。
Yeah, but it's really something...
2回の高。
Twice as tall.
ということで、皆さん本日はね、え、参加していただいてありがとうございました。
And with that, everyone, thank you for participating today.
どうでしたか？ちょっとあの、じゃあ感想一言ずついただけますか？まずは
How was it? Uhm, well, could I get a quick comment from each of you? First up...
え、じゃあおかゆさんから。
Uh, well, from Okayu-san.
はい。もうまずはね、本当にお誕生日おめでとうございます。
Yes. Well, first of all, happy birthday.
ああ、ありがとう、ありがとう！そうなんだ、そういうことだった
Ah, thank you, thank you! That's right, so that was it.
そういえば、ありがとう、ありがとう。本当におめでとうございます。
Come to think of it. Thank you, thank you. Truly, congratulations.
まあ、またね、こういう機会があったら是非呼んでください。ありがとうございました。
Well, if you have another chance like this, please invite me. Thank you very much.
ありがとう、参加してくれて。じゃあ続いて、マリン、お願いします。
Thank you for participating. Okay, next up, Marine, please.
まあ、まずはスバルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます。
Well, first of all, Subaru-san, happy birthday.
ま、常闇トワさん？一応今日優勝ということになってますけど、1億10点？
And, Tokoyami Towa-san? You're the winner today, I guess, but with 100,000,010 points?
うん。おめでとうございます。
Yeah. Congratulations.
なんか、そんなんで喜べるのかって。
I wonder if you can really be happy about something like that.
あの、マリンは言っときますけど、あなたを優勝者とは認めません。
Let me just say, I don't recognize you as the winner.
今回の優勝者は猫又おかゆさんです。
This time, the winner is Nekomata Okayu-san!
やったー！嬉しい！やったー！
Yay! I'm so happy! Yay!
もう、ごね得だぜ、これは。
You got that by complaining!
ああ、まあ、そういうこともあるか。まあじゃあマーちゃん、次回あったらね、頑張ってください。
Ah, well, I guess that happens. Well then, Ma-chan, do your best next time.
はい。じゃあ続いて、えー、ミオしゃん、お願いします。
Okay. Next up, uh, Mio-shan, please.
はい。えーと、うちはまだまだスバルのね、分かってあげられてないというか、未熟でしたが
Yes. Um, as for me, I guess I still don't understand Subaru well enough, I was still immature, but...
そんなことないよ、ミオしゃん！そんなことない！
That's not true, Mio-shan! That's not true at all!
まあまあまあ、そんなこと言うなって。お前が言うな、なんかドヤ顔。
Now, now, now, don't say things like that. You're one to talk, with that smug look.
お前、来いお前、お前！
You, come on you, you!
でも、でもあの、トワはいつもあの、スバルの家の洗濯物畳んでるのは確かなので
But, but, you know, Towa is always folding the laundry at Subaru's house for sure...
あの、優勝しててもいいのかなと思いますけど
...so I think it's okay for me to be the winner.
なにそれ。いやミオちゃんをかばってるやん。
What's that about? No, you're just defending Mio-chan.
今日誕生日おめでとう、スバル！あ、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Happy birthday today, Subaru! Ah, thank you, thank you!
ぬいぐるみ、買います。以上です。ぬいぐるみ！ありがとうございます。よろしくお願いします。
I'll buy you a plushie. That is all. A plushie! Thank you very much. I'll be counting on you.
じゃあ続いて、じゃあ、優勝したトワ、一言いただけますか？
Okay, next, then, the winner, Towa, can we have a word from you?
I'm winner.
なんでそんな息巻いてるんだ？バカ！すごい自信。
Why are you so fired up? Idiot! So confident.
マリンに謝れよ！おかゆに謝れ！おかゆに謝れ、お前！
Apologize to Marine! Apologize to Okayu! Apologize to Okayu, you!
おかゆさんは本当に素晴らしかったと思うんですけど、何が勝敗を分けたかというと、やはり洗濯物を畳んでるか畳んでないか
I think Okayu-san was truly wonderful, but what decided the match was, after all, whether you fold the laundry or not.
それはでかい。まあ、確かにでかいか。
That's huge! Well, that is pretty huge, I guess.
やはりあの、口と手を両方動かしてた私、選択を、洗濯物を畳んでいた私がやっぱり優勝したということで
After all, me, who was moving both my mouth and my hands, while folding Subaru's laundry, I'm the winner after all.
ありがとうございます。スバルさん、お誕生日おめでとうございます。
Thank you. Subaru-san, happy birthday.
また泊まり行きますね。ああ、よろしくお願いします。ありがとうございます。
I'll come stay over again, okay? Ah, please do. Thank you.
じゃあ最後に、みこち、お願いします。
Okay, lastly, Miko-chi, please.
はい。え、本日、え、お誕生日おめでとうございます！あ、ありがとう、ありがとう！
Yes. Uh, today, uh, happy birthday! Ah, thank you, thank you!
あの、確かにあの、みこちゃん、洗濯物全然知らなかったなって思って、ここで新事実をね、知れてよかったなって思います。
You know, it's true, Miko didn't know anything about the laundry at all, and I'm glad I got to learn this new fact here.
あ、洗濯物のこと知らなかったんだ？
Oh, you didn't know about the laundry?
え、知らなかった。そんなとこメモしなかった。
Huh? I didn't know. I didn't make a note of that.
普通にすばちゃんの家に行って、あの人ダメにするソファで、あのゴロンてする感じだったから
I just go to Suba-chan's house and lie down on that 'sofa that ruins people'.
みこちさ、自分がさ、家事を全然やらないから目に入らなかった
Miko-chi, because you don't do any chores yourself, it didn't even register to you.
ほんと、そう、何も違和感感じなかったもんね。
Really, I didn't feel anything weird at all.
洗濯物が溜まっているということに特に気にならないんじゃないですか？
Aren't you not particularly bothered by the laundry piling up?
うん、気になんない。ね、溜めちゃうだもん。
Yeah, I don't mind. I tend to let it pile up.
ああ、そういうことか。
Oh, so that's it.
マジで。スバルも気になんないから
Seriously. Since I don't mind either,
みんなそんなに気にしてたんだって今日マジでびっくりした。
I was really shocked today that everyone was so concerned.
同類が故の気付かなさ。
We're oblivious because we're the same type.
びっくりした。みんなそんなもんかと思ってた。ね？
I was surprised. I thought everyone was like that. Right?
同族か。
We're the same, huh.
でもね、みんなね、なんだかんださ、やいやい言いながらもね
But you know, even though everyone complains and all,
あのスバちゃんのことが大好きなんだなってにこちゃん思いましたので。
I realized that everyone really loves Subaru-chan.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you.
おめでとうございます。ありがとうね、みんな。
Congratulations. Thank you, everyone.
ありがとう、みんな。
Thank you, everyone.
喜んでいきます。
I'll gladly accept.
はい。はい、ということで、ちょっとこのちっちゃい感も。
Yes. So, and also, Miko-chan's tiny feeling too.
（笑い声）ちっちゃい感も。
(Laughter) The tiny feeling...
（笑い声）なんでちっちゃくなってるの？
(Laughter) Why did it get so small?
ちっちゃくなってて。
It got smaller.
はいはい、でかく、でかくしときました、でかくね。
Yes, yes, I made it bigger, right?
ありがとう。
Thank you.
はい、ということで、ちゃんとこの。
Alright, so, this is...
（笑い声）はい、ということで
(Laughter) Okay, so...
今日はね、皆さん参加していただいてありがとうございました。
Thank you, everyone, for participating today.
そしてね、見ていただいたね、皆さんもね、え、本当にありがとうございました。
And to everyone watching, thank you so much as well.
最後なんかみんな告知とかある？よかったら。
Finally, does anyone have any announcements?
大丈夫？
Are we good?
え？大丈夫です。
Huh? All good.
大丈夫です。
All good.
大丈夫ですか？はい。
Are we good? Okay.
じゃあ、最後は、おつしゅばーでいい？
Alright, then, should we end with 'Otsu-Shuba~'?
おお。もちろんですよ。え？
Oh. Of course. Huh?
（笑い）やばい、1億10点さんが
(Laughter) Oh no, the 110 million point person
1億10点かぶったらこんな、1億10点こんな動きすんのよ。
if they get 110 million points, this is how they move.
1億10点ボイス。1億10点ボイス。
The 110 million point voice. The 110 million point voice.
え、でもこの帽子はおかゆにあげてほしいよな、ちょっと。いいと。
But I kinda want you to give this hat to Okayu. It's nice.
うん、いや、お前被る資格ねえ、脱げ！
Yeah, no, you don't deserve to wear it. Take it off!
なんで？せっかくもらったのに？この帽子と共に？
Why? After I finally got it? Along with this hat?
まあまあまあまあ。
Now, now, now.
洗濯物畳んでんだよこっちはよ。
I'm folding laundry over here.
そうだよ、洗濯物畳んでるからね。
That's right, 'cause I'm folding laundry.
ちっちゃいやつが。
The tiny one is.
はい、じゃあ洗濯物。
Okay, so, laundry...
じゃあ、洗濯物持ちで皆さんおつしゅばって言って終わりますよ。
So, while holding laundry, we'll end by saying 'Otsu-shuba'.
そろそろ、はい。
It's about time, okay.
はい。はい。
Okay. Okay.
じゃあ皆さんありがとうございました。
Alright everyone, thank you so much.
いくよ、せーの
Ready? Set...
おつしゅばー！
Otsu-Shuba~!
バイバイ！ばーいばい。
Bye-bye! Bye-bye.
チャンネル登録高評価お願いします！
Subscribe and like my channel!